Surgery, round 2

Day 01033: Wednesday, 2018 January 03

Dental work

Supposedly, it was only supposed to take me half an hour to get to the dentists' office in Eugene by bike if I didn't get lost again or held up. I gave myself a full hour to get there though, just to be safe. I considered bringing my laptop to work on coursework during the half-hour waiting period, but decided I'd just use that time to rest and mentally prepare myself. My mobile's been getting worse, and now the screen won't stop turning on and off. That makes it a pain to work with when I'm trying to use it, but also means that the thing can't hold a charge, as the screen won't stay off for any length of time. Without my mobile, I had no timekeeper on my way there. Once I arrived, I asked the receptionist for the time, and I found I'd only gotten there ten minutes before my scheduled appointment. I don't know who programs the time-estimating functionality for these mapping programs, but it could really use some work.

So the dental assistant comes to get me shortly after I've checked in, and explains that the roots don't always actually have to be removed. I might just be sent home. That said, there's no radiograph of the situation in my mouth from after the last surgery, as no one ever took one afterwards. They need to take a radiograph, let the surgeon look at it, and let them decide if any work needs to be done. They ask if I want to have the surgery, if needed, today. Um. Yeah? I was told I was scheduling an appointment for surgery, not an appointment to see if I needed surgery on a later date. Of course I want to get this done! They asked me if I have any heart problems, liver problems, kidney problems, et cetera. I thought to myself, "Does having rainbows in my heart count as a heart problem?". I didn't say that out loud though; of course that's not a heart problem; while it's up for debate whether it qualifies as a problem at all, it's a brain issue, not a heart issue. The assistant takes the image, takes a look, and without the surgeon having seen it yet, says that yeah, the roots do have to come out after all. The original dentist knew what they were talking about when they referred me.

The oral surgeon comes in and checks it out, and decides that there are options. They explain that in cases where that much of the roots are left, there are usually problems. They don't always happen right away; it might be three years before the roots start causing me issues; but there's a high chance that these roots will need to be extracted eventually. I can hold off on the surgery, getting it if an when needed. Or I can get the surgery now, and not worry about it later. My gums have partly healed over by now because we waited too long; this was no fault of my own, but the combined fact that the other dental office never contacted me like they said they would and that the surgeon was on vacation by the time I got the necessary information, and needed to return before performing any procedures. My guess is that the surgeon would need to cut into my gums further, reversing the healing a bit, if done today. If I waited, it'd be a whole new injury and whole new healing process. Waiting seemed like a terrible idea. I asked about the nerve near the tooth roots and what the dentist had likely been worried about. It turns out that if the nerve there is damaged, a section of my face will go numb. Depending on the level of damage, the numbness will go away when the swelling goes down, but it could be permanent. I could end up with a permanent numb patch on my face near my lip. They assured me it wouldn't affect my use of the lip though, nor would it impact my appearance. I guess those are the things that matter. They said the likelihood of damage was low though, as the nerve didn't look like it'd be in their way when operating.

The surgeon tried to remove the roots without drilling, but like the dentist, was unable to. They ended up drilling away at the bone to open up space to get the tooth roots out. I now have two stitches on that side as well.

In a week's time, I have an appointment to return so they can check on the healing process. They said if I'm feeling well, I can telephone them, let them know I'm fine, and cancel the appointment. I told them a couple times I don't have telephone service, but it bounced right off them. They insist I should track down someone that *does* have telephone service and borrow it. Um. No. Not going to happen. I'll just go in for the appointment, no matter what sort of weather I have to deal with to get there. (Speaking of which, today's weather was great for a bike ride! The appointment, even if I was willing to call it off at the last minute, prevents the scheduling of my next operative appointment for a bit. I'll need to get a few cavities filled when I can though.

As a side note, the surgeon asked me how to pronounce my name. I explained, and they said that's what they'd guessed it was. Assuming the surgeon was being honest, they are probably the first person besides myself to have either actually thought it through or immediately realised that the wye has to be a *vowel* in my name, as no other vowels are present. As a vowel, it can't make its consonant sound. Most people try to have the wye make both its consonant sound *and* its vowel sound, but there's only one wye; it can't do both. I'm Alex Yst, not Alex Yyst! I regret though not asking the surgeon how they thought it was pronounced before telling them; I'll never know if they were just trying to make it sound like my name's spelling was reasonable or if they actually can read unrecognised words better than the average person. I didn't even think to ask about their guess, as no one else has ever gotten it right. In the future, I should try to get people to guess before telling them.

I still feel pretty good today. I don't seem to be having the severe day zero mood, energy, and physical pain issues I had for the past two surgeries. Well, I'm drained energy-wise, but not nearly as badly as before.

University of Drudgery

I had a lot to finish up today, seeing as having to build my own assembler took up so much of my time. I had discussion posts, grading, and quizzes to finish ... I haven't had time to complete the unit's reading materials yet, so I had to take the graded quiz half blind. I'll finish the reading material tomorrow. As such, I'll also finish the learning journal assignments tomorrow. I also had to put the finishing touches on the main assignment for the week today.

I wasn't too concerned with needing to finish this week's unit tomorrow and losing that day from next unit because of the structure of these courses and the current timing. The next unit is the eighth, and only once have I even been assigned anything more than discussion assignments and learning journal assignments during the eight unit of any course at this school. And that once that I was, it was a big essay that turned out (after I'd poured a bunch of effort into it) not to be graded. The reason for the lack of big assignments is because of the structure of the courses. The big assignments are peer-graded during the unit after they're due, and the ninth unit has nothing but the final exam. As there's no peer grading going on in the ninth unit, there can't be any big assignments during the eighth unit. Taking a week at next unit's materials this time though ... There're no discussion assignments! All I have to do is read and take my usual notes in the form of a learning journal entry. Seeing that, I rested from the surgery instead of focusing on catching up. This coming week will be nothing.

I'm going to have a bit of a break from school coming up soon. I should take that time to look for a job, if I'm up for it. It'd be just lovely on several levels to be able to leave behind the job I have now.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Nextdoor

Day 01036: Saturday, 2018 January 06

Social media

I was invited to join a neighbourhood-based social network today called Nextdoor. I figured I'd check it out, see that there was some problem (such as IP address discrimination, which some providers engage in, or noxious demands for photo ID, like Facebook engages in), but the only real problem I'm seeing is that it requires JavaScript for anything at all besides a blank page to render. Clearly, the site's poorly designed, but I don't think it has any malicious features at the moment. It does have address verification though. You seem to need an invite code to get on. Without one, you can join, but it might require verifying a code they send you after you provide your address. I'm not too concerned with that type of thing though; I'm not hiding. I probably won't use the site much while school is in session, as flipping JavaScript off (to use the university website) and on (to use Nextdoor) will be a pain, but I might check it out more between terms. It's got listings for yard sales and and individual items for sale, so it could come in handy when I'm looking for stuff.

Domain name consideration

I'm thinking about getting another domain name for use exclusively for URI-shortening. For example, my referral link for that new social network I'm on is long and looks like gobbledegook. In person, it'd be nice to have a shorter representation that'd redirect to the proper page. I don't want that sort of thing built into my main website or any subdomain of my main domain; I want the URIs that use my main domain to be mostly permanent (for the duration of my own life span, anyway), while I can easily see a reason I'd take down a shortened redirect eventually.

There are things to consider when choosing a domain though. How much am I willing to pay (yearly) for this side domain? How nice of a domain do I want it to be? These two I guess are the main things to think about. Lowering the price lowers the quality of the domain, while raising the quality will raise the price. At one end of the spectrum, I have the domains under my five favourite TLDs. Of these, //st. is the least expensive, while the others provide equal or lesser service of a higher price. At the other end, we have domains under the //tk. TLD, which is a perfectly valid ccTLD, but has a bad reputation due to the low-quality content its zero-dollar price tag attracts. Also, if you choose not to pay for a domain name there, they have the right to revoke your name at any time with or without reason, and certain extra rules are imposed on you. In the middle, we have paid domains, most of the ones in this quality level being under gTLDs. Some ccTLDs exist at this level too, though if I don't go with a //st. name, I'm probably either trying to save money or trying to use a TLD I think people will recognise. Speaking of which, that's another point to consider: the recognisability of the TLD I choose.

University drudgery

I set aside my available time today to complete the reading assignment in one of my courses. It's worth noting that the reading assignment in the other course is not accessible because the server it's hosted on maliciously discriminates against certain IP addresses. I have tested and confirmed this. However, I'm playing dumb about it a bit in class because people get weird and blame us proxy users instead of blaming those actually causing the problem: those that maliciously discriminate against proxy users. Anyway, it's not likely I'll be able to complete that reading assignment, though if a fellow student offers me a copy of the text (for example, that they download and rehost elsewhere), I'll happily take the time to read it and learn the material. I'm way too apathetic about my coursework to jump through any major hoops though or even to ask for help. I've expressed in the class forum that the server refuses to send me the file and I've expressed a concern that the material might be on the exam and I won't know that material. If someone feels like helping, I'll certainly be thankful, but I'm not going to sweat it if no one offers. Especially this week.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Irrational fear and the itching

Day 01039: Tuesday, 2018 January 09

Irrational fear

Late last night as I was trying to get to sleep, I had a sudden fear that I wouldn't get everything done on time at the university. Where did that even come from? I was slightly *ahead* of schedule! Anyway, I ended up staying up late to study and them take the four quizzes I had left to do. So now I'm done, other than my learning journal assignments. On these open-ended ones though, I like to include my final exam thoughts in the final entry, which means I won't be able to finish my learning journal entries for about another two days, and I'll have to turn them in at the last minute. I've doubled checked, and they're due just after the final exam period begins, so I can do as planned without there being any late submission issues.

Come to think of it, this is particularly simple because of the lack of proctored exams in these courses. In the proctored courses I took so far, we didn't have these open-ended learning journal assignments, but if I ever end up in a course with both proctored exams and open-ended learning journal assignments, I'm going to be racing against the clock.

With all that I can get done done, I pretty much have tomorrow off until around 21:00, when the final exam period opens. Well, I have it off from school and work, anyway. I still need to make it to a dental appointment in the Eugene office, go to the Springfield office to set up my next appointment, and try to visit my mother again. It helps that the route I take to and from the Eugene office leads right past the Springfield office. Come to think of it, I'd also like to get my rainbow heart tee-shirt repaired tomorrow. I've been putting that off for so long, so I haven't been able to wear it.

Dream journal

I dreamed I was looking at my most recent pay cheque, and it was for less than one hundred dollars. That couldn't be right. I tried looking into the cause on my credit card bill, because apparently in the dream, my credit card bill was deducted directly from my pay cheques. What I found was that my last surgery wasn't covered by my insurance.

The itching

My arm started getting really itchy today after I got home from my usual Tuesday errands. At first, I couldn't figure out what was going on, but this is probably the beginnings of a reaction to the amoxicillin. The time frame matches up. It's been about ten days since I quit taking the stuff. Currently, it's only my lower left arm and my right shoulder that are affected, so hopefully it doesn't get any worse. But it will. Scratch that. Now it's got my lower right leg and my the side of my left hand as well. My appointment with the surgeon is tomorrow. Wouldn't that be just lovely if I were covered in hives by then? Joy.

Sandwich wrappers

I stopped at Subway for a sandwich on my way home. I didn't notice until I was about to head to work, but in addition to the inner paper, they wrapped it in no less than *six* of the usual outer paper. What were they thinking!? I wonder if there's something I could do with these extra wrappers. It seems like a waste just to recycle them, but that's probably what I'm going to do.

Scheduling

As I was getting ready to go to work, I happened to check my schedule to make sure I'd be there on time. It said I wasn't supposed to work today. Had I transcribed it wrong when I was copying it from the schedule list at work? If I'd noticed right away, I could have planned for this different schedule, but I'd been counting on working Tuesday like I've been doing recently and having Thursday off. I headed to work as usual, just in case I'd written it down wrong, but sure enough, I had the day off. Huh.

That means I won't have much time on Thursday to finish my final exams. I'll have all the time I need and more, but only if I get on them right away. It also means I skipped certain errands on my usual Tuesday errand run because I didn't think I had time; I only did the bare minimum: hit up Bi-Mart for their lucky number day and deposit my pay cheque at the credit union.

On a more positive note, I was able to get some errands run that I wasn't expecting to get to today. I got my power bill paid; it was higher than I'd've liked it to be, but lower than I feared it'd be with my heat turned up. That said, I don't have it turned up super high, just high enough to not shiver. I still like a slight chill in the air. I also finally got around to returning about half of the bottles I've collected from my coworkers this term. I didn't feel up to returning them near the beginning of the term, and there was too much on my plate (such as my mother's holiday) near the end. The box I keep them in was overflowing, and I've had to put them in the other box, which I normally keep only shredded paper in (to later be thoroughly mixed when there's enough, then recycled in different cans). I'd've returned them all, but there's a limit to how many stores will take each day. I've got two nearby convenience stores that'll take fifty each, so I paid a visit to both of them. I also had time to get my laundry done for the week, something I thought I'd have to put off a day or two longer.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Scheduling a delay

Day 01040: Wednesday, 2018 January 10

Site update schedule

I wasn't feeling that great, so I didn't put a lot of thought into my update schedule of this website, which includes both canary chirping and journal page uploads. It used to also include the public archival of my coursework for the week, which in fact has been the reason I've needed to slow down and not post daily. The less-frequent updates meant I didn't have to polish my partly-completed coursework into something presentable each day; I could wait until the work was complete and only polish it as a whole. That way, I didn't waste time polishing parts that would later be worked or even deleted. My coursework schedule is still the driving force behind my update schedule, despite the lack of visible archival. For this reason, I've reworked the schedule slightly into something a little more convenient. Each term, the week just before I fall silent (my silent period includes the span between terms and six days into the beginning of the next term), I'm going to delay my site update by a day. While most updates fall on Wednesdays, this one will fall on a Thursday. This buys me an extra day on the final assignments for the term and gives me adequate time to reasonably complete my final exams.

Consequently, this week's update was originally scheduled for upload today. This has now been postponed until tomorrow. I took my exams for the term tonight and wrote up my short reports on them; I will format the reports and submit them tomorrow before work.

Health

Over the past week, I've felt much gayer than I have been lately. I'm really thinking the infected teeth were the main thing bringing me down. The school certainly did a number to me emotionally, but I'm not so convinced they were the main problem any more. I'm not quite back to what I was before, but I'm definitely enjoying what's come back to me so far, and I expect the rest shouldn't be too far behind.

Over the past few days, I've also noticed that my stomach has gotten hairier. I'm almost certain I wasn't this hairy before. My breasts were, but not my stomach. I wonder what that's about.

The surgeon said my gums are healing up nicely. The Eugene dentists' office was even able to schedule my next appointment at the Springfield office, so I didn't need to stop there on the way home.

Visit

I really wasn't feeling up to dealing with my mother today, but it's been too long since I've visited her. It's not for lack of trying, but she's never around and she doesn't answer her messages (because her mobile was designed by a screwy company (Apple) and uses a screwy service provider (Verizon), so messages don't even make it to her much of the time. She gets lonely though, so I try to drop by when there's time. I'm about to be very busy, if I can keep my motivation up, so I dropped by today in a third attempt to visit her. Predictably, she wasn't around. This time though, Vanessa was. We talked for an hour or two, and I found out my timing wasn't quite as bad as I'd thought it'd been these past times. It's not that our mother's been out *frequently* lately, it's that she's been out for *extended periods* lately. She's been gone for about five days at a time at least twice now. I should have better luck if I try back on Saturday. Maybe. Between periods of extended departure, she's also been having shorter day trips, so I still could miss her.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The cleaning

Day 01041: Thursday, 2018 January 11

Apartment cleaning

Having closed the book on this past term, it's time for me to begin looking for a better job so I can escape the one I have now. I was debating between going out to look at the working conditions of a few places and just staying at home and applying for various jobs online. I took a look at the weather though, and decided to stay indoors.

I went to dig dig up the paper I wrote my neighbour's telephone number on for use as an emergency contact, but I couldn't find it. During the first half of the term, when I really wasn't feeling up to much, I let my bedroom deteriorate into a mess. I'd have to spend the day cleaning it if I wanted any hope of finding that number, but more importantly, if I don't want to continue losing things. I knew I likely wouldn't find the number either way though, and that I'd probably have to suck it up and ask for the number again.

I might spend the bulk of or even all of my time off from school just focussing on getting this place organised. I needed a better way to store socks and underwear, for example. I bought a drawer set to hold them a while back, but it's tiny and wouldn't even hold all my underwear, let alone my socks. Besides, when my mother invited herself to store stuff at my place again, I dumped it out and used it to store the small computer components I'd had in the corner of my living room. Due to my mother taking my living room (even though she's not using it), I've had to cram a lot into my bedroom and entryway that don't belong there as well, making both areas difficult to use. If I can get everything organised and keep it that way, the coming term should be easier. I'll just stick with my current stupid job another term, then apply elsewhere during the next break, if nothing goes horribly wrong again.

Between restlessness and the fact that progress would be slowed until I could get my socks and underwear out of the way, I decided to play a visit to a local second-hand store to look for some plastic drawer sets. I biked to get there, thinking there'd be no way I'd find what I was looking for, and that I'd probably end up doing some clothing shopping while I was there. Instead, I found not one, but four wide drawer sets. I paid more than I wanted to to get two of them, but time is of the essence. The sooner I get organised, the better off I'll be. I left the other two there, my excuse to myself being that they were more expensive than the two I bought, despite being identical. In all honesty though, I didn't know what I'd do with another two sets at the moment, with most of my space unusable, as it's been set aside for my mother's use. Thankfully, my workplace is next door to the second-hand shop, so I was able to leave my bike there and walk home with my purchase. I wasn't sure at first that I had a use for all six (three in each set) drawers, but after taking another look at my situation, I think six is exactly how many I need, at a minimum. For example, if I want to get my larger computer parts put in some, I'll need more. After finding the top could be removed and the drawers could stack, I might pick up the other two sets tomorrow.

A fixed schedule

I heard a rumour today at work that the head manager is going to be implementing a fixed schedule soon. If true, that'll be awesome! If I'm going to be there a while longer, it'll be nice to know weeks in advance when I'll be working and not. I've been scheduling dental work, for example, base don guesses as to when I'll be able to make it in. If I end up working on those days at those times, I'll need to cancel my appointment and make a new one, postponing the work further. I also sometimes gamble with my coursework, assuming I'll have certain days off, just because I need a break. Usually, it works out, but sometimes, it results in a mad rush that leaves me more tired than before.

Vacation

My vacation from school begins today. School won't begin again until next month, so it'll be until about a week into next month until I update the website again. Have a great break everyone, and I hope to see you next term.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

*sigh*

Day 01042: Friday, 2018 January 12

Don't provoke people

I've never been one to try to step on people's toes. If I can at all avoid it, I try to avoid getting on people's nerves. Today, I was reminded once again why this is the safest course of action. As I was headed out, some person called me over to see if I'd seen the person they were looking for. Thankfully, I hadn't, so I wasn't able to help them find their target before learning their intent. It seems the target flashed their genitals at them in a public restroom, and now, they were chasing the target down to beat them up over it. Wow.

I've never understood why getting flashed sets people off. It shouldn't really bother anyone; it doesn't hurt you in any way to catch a glimpse of some animal's reproductive organs if those organs aren't invading your space. And that's what we are: animals. You don't go beat up dogs you see if their reproductive organs show, do you? The only difference I see is that flashers are *trying* to bother you. So why let it bother you? Why let them have their way? On a slightly-related tangent, the local laws against public nudity also seem ridiculous. I mean, why are people so offended by the natural human form? That said, I do prefer people keep their clothing on in public, clothing looks better than bodies; I just don't think it should be illegal to do otherwise.

The cleaning

I headed to the second-hand shop again, hoping those plastic drawer sets were still around. I figured they probably were, seeing as it'd only been a day since I'd seen them and, quite frankly, they were overpriced. Not only were the two I'd seen yesterday still there, three more had shown up at lower prices. The catch though was that they didn't match the originals. Obviously, I don't care about the fact that they *look* a little different, but the two cheapest ones won't stack due to being different models. There's not really a stacking standard for when they produce these things. The next one up was identical to the two I had and the two I left behind yesterday, but it's off-colour. Still, it's identical shape makes it stackable with the rest, so I picked it up for its lower price tag along with one of the two remaining from yesterday.

I actually tried to stack the other two in the store before finding it wasn't going to work. It makes me wonder if I should get that fifth drawer set like the four I now have. I'm really not sure I need five, but at the same time, if this one gets away and I change my mind later, I may not find any more that stack with these. That's the drawback of shopping second-hand. On second thought, I won't buy it. These things can only stack two high before they get too high for the top drawers to even be usable. Without a sixth, the stackability of the fifth won't be useful.

While sorting paperwork, I found a bill for one of my credit cards. Among the items listed in the transaction overview is an automatic payment that brings the balance to $0. However, they enclosed an envelope so I could pay the bill. Um. What? What do you want me to even send you? They need to work on whatever automated mailer program sends these things so it doesn't send envelopes when nothing is due.

University drudgery

After the university pulled their garbage, I was sure I was going to leave their ambassador program, a program they use to get existing students to help them recruit more students. After all, I've become disillusioned with the school because of their threats and censorship demands, so I see no reason to help them recruit. I was just waiting for the right moment. I wasn't sure it'd go over well if I drop out of the program as soon as they threaten me. How would they react? It didn't seem like a safe gamble. With that in mind, I figured I'd wait until their next assignment for me, which would likely be one I coundn't actually help with like most of the others, and I'd leave citing the fact that I'm a poor fit for the program and it's a poor fit for me. I mean, last time, they wanted testimonials from students, but they wouldn't even let me provide my story unless I was willing to let them use my face. Um, hello? That's ridiculous! And not being cisgendered, I've never been comfortable with my appearance.

The people running the program hardly ever contact me though, so it's taken until now to set the plan in motion. And, it's not even an assignment; it's a notification that the program has set up a Facebook group for internal communication. It was a perfect excuse to leave though; if a Facebook account is required for learning what they want from us, someone without a Facebook account, such as myself, isn't going to do well in the program. If they tried to get me to set up a Facebook account to remedy the program, I'd cite Facebook's noxious demands for photo ID as why that's not an option. What I didn't expect though was a response telling me that the group was "still" on Yammer (Microsoft's social network, because all the big companies have their own social network these days), and that the Facebook group is just an alternative for those that don't check Yammer that often. So this is why I've been getting almost no updates or assignments. They've been on Yammer the whole time, and I had no idea. I thought this was done via email.

Over a year ago, I had issues getting Yammer to work. Simply put, it'd let me log in, but would present me with a mostly-blank page as soon as I would. There wasn't a way to see or do anything. I reached out to the school for help, as they claim this to be their own social network (it's actually a walled garden within Microsoft's Yammer social network), and got no response whatsoever. So now, over a year later, I try again (to get a screenshot and explain that Yammer isn't working and hasn't been working. The plan was to tell them they could either help resolve the issue, point me to someone that could, or drop me from the program as I'd initially requested. It works now though, though it requires JavaScript to do so. That's going to mean I don't use the platform often. I'll be staying in the program a bit longer, too. Aside from the recruitment assignments, it looks like we also help existing students figure things out. If you're already here, I don't mind helping you, though I don't think I want to draw new students into this mess of a school. The censorship and the unwarranted threats are why I'm not interested in recruitment, but to be honest, those are far from the only problems here at the university. I don't feel like going into details yet again, but if you've been reading my journal, you know what I mean. Or maybe you don't; those pages may have needed to be censored. Isn't censorship great? *sigh*

Escape

It dawned on me today (after I'd spent the day organising) that I really need to escape my stupid job. I don't have time to focus on cleaning and organising right now! It was probably a great move to get these storage drawers and begin sorting stuff into them. Simply having the drawers there will help prevent the mess from getting any worse. I didn't have time to look for organisation options while school was in session. I can slowly improve my situation when time is short but still somewhat available: when I'm back in school. Now that I have the drawers, finding a new job needs to take priority.

As predicted, I'll have to suck it up and ask my neighbour for their telephone number again to put them down as an emergency contact.

I don't have time tomorrow to begin the job hunt though. I'm going to try to visit my mother as already planned.

The fire

I'm not sure what happened exactly, but the boxes containing a pizza and a cheese bread in our warmer at work caught fire. No one was hurt and nothing, aside from the product, was damaged. The warmer still looks fine and none of the heating elements are exposed. I'm baffled as to how the boxes got hot enough to ignite.

Mobile inconveniences

Not having a working mobile device is kind of inconvenient. I use the thing as a timer. I use it as a camera. I use it as a music player. I use it as a scheduling calendar. I use the thing to receive emails on the go. Sometimes, I even do a quick Web search.

Having a working mobile device is inconvenient too though. Without freedom-friendly hardware, battery life is short. I mean, my last mobile had a cracked battery, so of course it wasn't going to last too long. The mobile I had before that one though, my first mobile, was brand new. It still couldn't go a full twenty-four hours without a charge. I also can't use the thing with Wi-Fi or Bluetooth, because the specifications of the hardware are kept too secret for the community to have what they need to program support for them. I can't say I've ever used Bluetooth for anything, though it'd be nice to have it for headphones, but Wi-Fi would make the device so much more useful than it already is.

If I could get a mobile with decent battery life or Wi-Fi support, I'd probably scrounge up the money to get a new one. However, as the situation holds, I can only see one strong motivating factor for getting a new mobile: email. I'm probably going to need to get telephone service for my job hunt. Once I have my new job though, I'll leave the telephone (be it a land line or mobile line) at home. My employer will still be able to reach me that way, but they'll have to either luck into hitting me when I'm at home or wait until I return so I can return respond to whatever message they leave. I have no obligation to be reachable by any method whatsoever when I'm out of the apartment on some errand or even just to enjoy my time off the clock. If I have mobile email though, an employer (or coworker) willing to use email may be encouraged to do so by my much-faster email response times.

No itching

I'm not sure what was up with the itching that one day, but I never broke out in hives and haven't been notably itchy since. I'd say it was the placebo effect, and that I was just feeling the itch because I'd been expecting it, but I'd actually forgotten about the possible allergy until my arm got really itchy and I looked up the day I finished the antibiotics in my journal. I don't think I'm actually allergic to the antibiotics after all, or if I am, I'm significantly less allergic than my mother and sister.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I'm one of the crazies

Day 01043: Saturday, 2018 January 13

Not the same person any more

Whoever I've become, I'm not the same person I was a year ago. I don't feel like the old me at all. I guess now I'm Alex, and before, I was [REDACTED]. That's really the only way to explain it. I've changed; metamorphosed. It feels so bizarre to think about, but so many of my thoughts and desires have changed over the past several months. I'm certainly much happier this way, but I'm pretty sure I'm a lot less sane. I live in a world of crazies though, so it's not like I don't fit in better this way.

Visiting my mother

As planned, I tried to visit my mother before work. She wasn't around. I had a short shift today though, and I was able to catch her after work. It'd be easier if she either checked her email or if she wasn't on a screwy mobile and screwy mobile service that drop messages to and from her. Thankfully, it seems she's started to become more reasonable on some levels lately, and she now says email is fine. Next time, I can reach her that way.

It sounds like she hasn't been doing to well lately. I won't go into details because that's her private matter, but I worry for her. I'll be meeting up with her again tomorrow, while things are somewhat slow for me.

Emergency contact

I've come to a realisation: not having an emergency contact is not likely to affect my chances of getting hired, despite the fact that the one business refuses to let me leave that field blank. I honestly don't have anyone I want contacted if something happens to me. Just send me to the hospital, and if I'm not conscious or something, let the medical professionals do what they think best. There does not exist someone in my life that I trust to make such decisions on my behalf; I trust strangers with medical training more than anyone I actually have a relationship with. Depending on what formats are accepted by the form in question, I'll probably just put 911, "no emergency contact available", or some variant of +15555550101 and call it good. If I'm wrong and they hold it against me, I guess so be it. I'll feel safer not having a contact listed in my file, so I'm better off at a job that I don't need one.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

There was no crush ...

Day 01044: Sunday, 2018 January 14

Dream journal

I dreamed my mother was expressing curiosity in the rationale behind what numbers could be the maximum a computer could store in a field. I was trying to explain powers of two to her, attempting to compare them to powers of ten and their relation to a maximum number of digits, but she wasn't understanding because she wouldn't stop interrupting. If I could form even a single complete sentence, maybe we could've gotten somewhere.

Visit

I spent the day with my mother, most of that time running errands on foot with her. It certainly beat sitting around at her place not getting anything accomplished. I forgot how much it hurts to run errands on foot though. By the time we got back, I had a blister on my right foot and I felt like I had one on my left foot as well. We also got back late, so I didn't have time to make dinner or rest before heading to work. I only had time to stop at home, drain my blister, change into my work uniform, and head out. It was certainly worth it though; I'm not complaining.

My mother seems to have lost interest in my dental work, which is good. I mean, she's curious, and also says I should go in to a general medical doctor for a check-up as I haven't had one in probably over a decade, but she's expressed no further interest in being at the appointments with me. I already had so many scenarios run through my head about how to deal with attempts that she might make to accompany me, with the worst-case scenario involving giving her the incorrect date so I'd have it done a day before she tried to go. This was only for if she pushed and wouldn't take "no" for an answer, but it was certainly something I'd thought about and even rehearsed several times in my head just in case. It's nice to know I'm not going to have to fight her about this.

She also mentioned a little girl I once knew. She used to hassle me about her, insisting I'd had a crush on her. I've told her so many times that I never did, but every couple years, she'd bring the topic up again and insist I did. Like, dude. I was asexual. Of course I wasn't developing crushes on *anyone*. She seemed to think though that I was still a normal hetero child on some level though. Now that I'm gay, I think she's finally grasped the fact that I never liked this girl. I mean, I thought she was nice as a classmate, but I never even made any attempts to befriend her. At least now though, my mother has stopped referring to her as the girl I had a crush on and is now referring to her as the girl she used to hassle me about.

My mother is an excellent bargain hunter. Her one fatal flaw though is that she often buys stuff she has no storage space for. Occasionally, she also buys stuff I'm convinced she doesn't actually have a use for, but maybe she later finds uses for these things. I don't know. She occasionally also finds bizarre food deals. Such as this time, she found a twenty-pound bag of red potatoes for two dollars. Like, what? Who is even discounting potatoes that steeply? The catch is that she had to buy in bulk, getting more potatoes than she'll be able to use before they expire, but she'll still save a lot of money with just the potatoes she'll use. You've got to figure that if she bought however many potatoes she's going to end up using from that deal in a normal store, it'd cost more that $2 USD. And now, she's planning to give away the excess to friends so they don't go to waste. So anyway, long story short, I now have a bunch of red potatoes in my cupboard. I bought some regular russets a couple days ago, so I won't be able to go through as many of the reds as I otherwise could, but the russets and reds together should make my soups a little more interesting.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.1 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Obscurity

Day 01045: Monday, 2018 January 15

Obscurity

Marc with a C has a new album up for release called Obscurity. It sounds like he's really excited about it and has been working on it in the background for a number of years. I'm interested to see how that turns out.

University drudgery

It seems my school is now offering the option to transfer in credits. As much as I'd like to get out faster, I'm not going to transfer anything in. First of all, I want as much of a break from my old life as possible. I don't want to try to dig up my old credits. And second, my old coursework was lost due to the event. I want to keep everything that ends up as part of my work that matters in my archive, as it's an important part of my personal history. If that means staying here at University of Drudgery a little while longer, so be it.

My feet are killing me today. I swear, my bike not only saves me a lot of time, but spares me a lot of pain. I wasn't really up to going out any more than necessary today, so I stayed at home and worked on job applications online. Besides, tomorrow and the next day are my days off. I'm going to need to have rested my feet as much as possible before then, as those are the days best suited for going out to check on what's out there and available in the area.

The job I worked on applying to today wanted the exact dates of my employment periods. I don't even have that information any more due to data loss, aside from my employment periods in the past three years. I mean, why would I keep track of exact dates of hire/departure? The only reason I even have the more recent dates is that they happen to be in my journal; so I needed to find my hire date for my current job there. I ended up not including my two-week temp job though, because they didn't know my by my current name, there was a span of a few months between that job and my current one that I'd need to try to explain, and it'd make it look lime my first job lasted only two weeks when that isn't the case. There were extenuating circumstances surrounding that dark period in my life.

I forgot that potential employers want the telephone numbers of past employers though. I wasn't able to finish the application, as I needed to get the telephone number of my current job, so I spent the rest of my free time for the day tidying up both my apartment and my website. I got the telephone number when I headed in to work, but by the time I got back home, it was rather late.

Website clean-up

This website is littered with poorly-built pages. The markup is perfect XHTML 5.1, but there are various semantic issues. Keeping a website has been a learning process, and I continue to improve, but many of my past pages still show a lack of quality. For the most part, I leave these pages alone, especially the big pages (because cleaning them up takes more time than it's worth) and the weblog pages (because they're far too numerous to reasonably process), but every once in a while, a big enough change occurs that some clean-up becomes mandatory.

The current problem is the misplacement of id attributes and the lack of <section/> elements. With changes I made in the CSS during the past term, pages that use ids don't look right unless those ids are properly made attributes of <section/> elements. (<section/>s linked to have a lit-up background.) In the past, I've used those attributes as a part of headings, but a while back, I started using <section/>s to divide content more semantically. I've already done a little cleaning in the past couple days, but today, with a temporary hindrance to my job hunt, I worked on cleaning the biggest of my messy pages: my ccTLD notes. When I take the time to fix a page, I fix it all the way, I don't just clean up the part that needs immediate attention. This page featured two hundred forty-nine ids that needed to be moved into <section/> elements that didn't yet exist, not to mention that nothing was properly indented and sentences in paragraphs were not properly placed on their own individual lines. It was a mess, but not any more. That said, it was a rush job. I think I got everything fixed, but there may be something I missed.

Work

Our head manager is only the head manager of our store location. They're not the top leader in the franchise. Someone higher than them, who doesn't work in the store, decided to reconfigure our computer system for no apparent reason. The most noticeable change is that the menu items have been rearranged. We'll relearn where everything is, but what was even the point of moving it? Next, one of the menu item buttons is now configured to stop functioning after 20:00, at which point it becomes greyed out. Again, why? It's one of the items we stop preparing after 20:00, but if they haven't sold as well as expected, we could still have some left over and still need that button, especially within the first several minutes after 20:00. More to the point though, there are other items we don't tend to try to keep ready after 20:00 as well. None of those other menu items end up greyed out. It's completely inconsistent. I've been blaming all the problems of the system on the system itself, but now I don't know what to think. Some of the problems are outright bugs. But other problems are strange quirks, and any of the non-bug quirks could be a configuration issue or a problem with the actually system. There's no way to know which.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Vivian

Day 01046: Tuesday, 2018 January 16

Dream journal

I can't remember the plot of the dream or most of the events, but near the end, a girl I know and I had just left a strange store with some other girl. She was definitely a girl and everyone recognised her as such, but based on build and voice, she was a transwoman who'd chosen not to go through hormone therapy whatsoever. She was comfortable being herself without bodily alterations. However, her make-up was on really thick to the point that her face was white; not just pale, but actually whiter than most paper. I wouldn't be too surprised if her make-up represented my opinion on make-up in general. Without exception, I think people look better without the stuff. It's actually one of the things that makes me find women unattractive, which leads me to believe my distaste for make-up is due to my mixed brain. I'm man enough to not want make-up on myself, but I'm woman enough not to want make-up on a partner.

As we left, our newly-met party member mentioned that the store we left, of which she was one of the owners and people running it, opened up pretty much whenever one of them got there. There were no set hours, and there were about five people that owned and helped run the place. I remember wondering how anyone was supposed to know when they could stop by to buy anything.

After leaving, we never entered any sort of building, but somehow, we ended up in some sort of long hall. I can't even remember what the hall looked like, but a telephone attached to the wall rang. While the others kept walking, I stopped to quickly answer it. "Yes?", I asked. There was no response for a couple seconds, then I heard my own ostensibly-recorded voice speak back to me. "Yes?" It was garbled a bit by the telephone line, but it was definitely me and definitely said exactly as I'd just said it. That weirded me out, so I hung up the telephone really quickly and ran slightly to catch up with the other girls. But then the dream skipped like a scratched record. I was back on the telephone hearing my own voice played back to me. "Yes?" Um, no. This was not going to keep happening. At this point, I pieced together that it was a dream, and I was not going to sit and get creeped out like this. I forced myself to wake up, thinking it was my only way to avoid a third iteration of the tiny loop.

As a side note, I should really force myself to wake up whenever I realise I'm dreaming. If you don't wake mid-dream, you don't remember any part of your dream. I'm not sure if I do that though; after all, if I don't wake up, intentionally or not, I can't remember the dream even happened. Even on a "dreamless" night, if you've had enough sleep, you've probably had about six to eight dreams; they're not a once-a-night occurrence like many people think they are.

Job hunt

I've decided not to look into apparent working conditions before applying at places. Mostly, I'd like some practice interviewing. Ruling places out before the interviews will limit how much practice I get. Once I'm offered a position, I can focus solely on that company and take a good look at how things appear to be run, at least from the outside. It'll also save me a lot of time looking into the conditions of positions I won't end up chosen for anyway.

I still went out as planned, my mission was just a little different. Instead of checking out places and employees, I just looked into what businesses are where and jotted down company names to later search for on the Web to find application forms or résumé-submission procedures. I decided to pay a visit to the Gateway Mall, as there're so many businesses in one place to apply at. I made a list of most of them, and will apply when time allows.

While I was there, I located the Food Industries Credit Union. I've seen people come through the drive-through lane at work with debit cards from there, but I've never actually seen the place. I've been curious as to what that actually is. Once I saw the place, a question arose to my mind: what are the requirements of membership? I work as a low-level fast food grunt. Not that I'd want a membership, is that enough to make me eligible for one? It turns out I'm eligible, but not because I work in the food industry. There are three requirements for membership. You've got to live in Lane County, you've got to pass their credit check, and you've got to put down a ten-dollar deposit. Well, I guess I only *assume* I'm eligible. I'd like to think I can pass their credit check, but there might be some issue because I don't have enough of a credit history or something. I actually got declined for a credit card once for not having enough credit history, though now, I'm glad I don't have that particular card anyway.

Getting a new laptop

I think I'll spend the day tomorrow getting a new laptop from the recycling centre. newdawn and morgan both died on me unexpectedly in the middle of terms. It'd be nice if I had a backup in case bailey dies unexpectedly too. That pretty much means tomorrow is not likely to be an overly-productive day, but while I'll lose this one day, it'll prevent me from losing multiple days during a period I have no time to spare. It's better I do this now and not later.

Vivian

My sister Vivian, previously known by a different name in these journal pages, has asked that I now redact her legal name and replace it with the name "Vivian". She's also asked that I remove instances of the name of her organisation. Both have been completed. Also as per her request, mentions of her after today will be kept to a minimum. I asked about if vague mentions are okay, and she kind of said they were, but doesn't seem too keen on the idea. If at all possible, today will be my last mention of her, though figuring out how to convey ideas not about her, but tangent to her, will certainly prove difficult. We'll see how I handle it as things come up. Or rather, *I'll* see. If everything goes perfectly, *you* won't.

Website maintenance

The website cleanup continues, with most of my work on it today consisting of old journal pages from the three-month period in which I'd started dividing up my journal content into sections using section headers, but hadn't yet started using proper <section/> elements yet. For the most part, I just went about the work without really reading the content of the pages, but a few titles caught my attention and I read a bit. I'm reminded of how terrible life used to be, only slightly longer than a year ago. And now, life is almost fantastic. Almost. I mean, the world is still a terrible mess, but I'm actually happy now. I'm still not in the best place ever, but I'm no longer in an emotionally toxic home. One particular passage really brought back memories:

For the record, living on my own will be a pain. I'm aware of that. However, I'm so close to breaking. My mind, my spirit ... I don't know how much longer I can stand to be here. Even if I fail at first, living on my own will give me a chance to break free of the chains that bind me here; a chance to not be constantly ridiculed for actually caring, for putting the good of the world above the good of the few. I'll be free to be me, free to stretch my arms and explore that it means to *be* me, without judgment, without fear of losing my home simply because I "misspoke", refused to eat corpses, or cut my hair differently. I just want ... to be what I really am, not what my mother wishes that I was.

For the record though, living on my own is not a pain; it's been awesome! Sure, it was a little rough in the beginning before I got some basic essentials brought in. And the growing pains of coming into myself drove me to the brink. But with those out of the way, this has been the best period of my life to date.

I also used to have to wash my laundry by hand in the bathtub ... can you even imagine having to do that every few days? Man, that really took a lot out of me. It wasn't the worst I was dealing with, but on top of everything that wore me out emotionally, I was worn out physically by this and the apartment-hunting.

I needed to put the maintenance on the back burner though to take care of a more-urgent matter: redaction. While redacting for Vivian, I noticed several other bad memories.

On the way to Springfield, our mother seemed quite surprised that Cyrus wasn't [his] usual chipper self. Does our mother not understand that other people have feelings? Our mother thoroughly railed on us both yesterday, why would either of us be chipper? I've learned to keep my emotions under wraps around our mother, but for Cyrus, it's all out there on [his] sleeve. Cyrus seemed lifeless and emotionally drained. In any sane world, why would Cyrus be any other way, given the circumstances?

Later in the day, my mother commented that [she doesn't] know how I can survive as a vegan. [She likes] to say that every once in a while. I replied that I survive barely, so [she] continued that vegetables don't really provide much energy. I dropped it on [her] that I indeed don't have energy because [she doesn't] want me to cook. Without a decent meal, I indeed don't feel well. I've been drained of energy for quite a while now. Though I didn't say it, it's not even like [she cares] what shape I'm in. [She is] put off by the smell of my cooking, and as a result, I don't get to even get decent nutrition. How can you claim to love someone while choosing their constant lethargia over you having to smell food that you don't personally find appetizing? Either my mother's sense of smell is off the charts (which [she]'ll argue isn't true) or [she has] zero concern for my well-being. I suppose I already know that, but it hurts to think about. My mother loves the *idea* of [her] children, but not [her] children themselves.

My mother went to bed, and when I said I'd stay up and continue lifting boxes, my mother claimed that while I may be stronger, [she is] tougher; I don't need to try to prove otherwise. My mother isn't even tough enough to try out new software, new music, or a new diet; I doubt whether [she's] somehow tougher than me. However, that wasn't at all the point. I explained that it had nothing to do with toughness, it had to do with not wanting to be a burden; I didn't want to be the one that slowed our mother down. My mother responded that I'm not a burden. That's not what [she] always [tells] me though whenever anything comes up. [She] always [tries] to shift blame onto me, even when it's not my responsibility to pick up [her] slack. You can't play both sides like that; it causes both both support and disdain to be felt as piercingly negative. In fact, [her] positive comments might hurt worse than [her] insults.

I confronted Cyrus again about [his] still [staying over] with our father. Personally, I don't mind if Cyrus has a relationship with our father, but Cyrus is going to be hit with the backlash from not keeping [his] word to our mother. Cyrus claimed that [he] thought that mother had said that [he] could stay. Our mother would never say that though. [She] worked very hard to berate Cyrus and tear [him] down in order to coerce [him] into giving up [his] time with our father, so [she's] not going to suddenly say that Cyrus can stay over at our father's place and hang out some more. I walked Cyrus through the situation one more time. I was hoping that [he]'d understand this time, but it turned out that it didn't matter anyway. Our mother confronted Cyrus later in the day about the issue, and has now told Cyrus that [she is] done with [him].

Not all of those negative emotions were directed at me, but there's a common theme, clearly. Our mother is one toxic individual. Rehashing these memories put me in a bit of a sour mood. It's like part of her has leached out into my journal, forever toxifying it. I guess, in a way, it has. She poured all of that into me, and rather than fully succumb to it, I poured as much of it as I could out of me and into the journal. It somewhat immortalised it, but it may have prevented its effect on me from becoming bad enough that I finally offed myself. I mean, there were many times I just wanted to die, but I didn't take it that far, likely because I still had an outlet. Not that it really matters, I guess; I still have to die one day and I'm only postponing the inevitable by not having died already. Anyway, the sooner I finish this little cleaning task, the sooner I can put the past back in the archives and come back to the present.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

This laptop sucks already.

Day 01047: Wednesday, 2018 January 17

Managing priorities

It's hard to manage priorities when there's so much that needs to be done and so little time to do it in. I kind of freaked out and thought I needed to escape my stupid job, but that should really be the least of my concerns right now. First and foremost, I have a shift leader right now that said they'd teach me how to drive. I don't know when I'll have another opportunity, since I don't have any family in the area beyond my parents and Vanessa. Vanessa's too young to be a driving teacher and she's just learning to drive herself, not to mention she'll be moving out of the area soon. My mother had her chance, she's moving soon with Vanessa, and she's really obnoxious on the road. I'm not sure I could stand to have her teach me. And if I have my father teach me and my mother ever found out, my mother would freak out. So basically, due to my mother's toxicity, I can't learn from either parent. I can't afford to leave my job until I take my shift leader up on their offer and I have my driver license. I need to do this between terms when I have time though. I don't think I should try to learn in only two weeks for my own benefit, not to mention that I don't want to take away all their time off the clock, so I should probably wait until the next break, which means I should spend the coming term at my current job, use the break to learn, spend the next term there too, and only *then* spend a break looking for a job. I can deal with my job a while longer, and I don't even know where I want to work yet anyway.

Perhaps more urgently though, I need to get organised as I said before, both physically and digitally. I need to do well in school, and I can't do that if I'm working through a mess. The virtual mess slows my coursework completion, while the physical mess slows a lot of other things, so it takes longer to even get to coursework.

Rehashing old memories

As I continued the website clean-up project today, I ran across a bizarre dream I'd written about. One passage was particular amusing because of how ill-behaved my mother was being:

Before I could get laundry started, in an actual washing machine too, I got called away to a celebratory dinner. Along the way, we were told that the meal would be all organic, at which point my mother showed up and tried to convince everyone that I choose what I eat out of hatred, and that I hate meat. They then tried to convince them that I also hate eggs, but only sometimes. Other times, I do eat them. I had to explain that no, I never eat eggs, but my mother kept contradicting this. Then my mother started questioning me about my policy on tomatoes, which I of course don't have. After I explained this, my mother said that I *should* have a policy on tomatoes, because tomatoes are known to cause diabetes and cancer. In fact, all plants are known to cause some sort of health problem. I wasn't sure what to do with this information though, as I'm not vegan for health reasons; this wouldn't convince me not to eat plants. Furthermore, meat is known to raise the risk of cancer as well.

For context on that first sentence, this was during a period I had no access to a washing machine or dryer. I was washing all my clothing by hand in the real world. I have no other notes though, the rest speaks for itself.

I've finished work in the journal, and all that remains are some learning journal pages which won't be seen for several years.

My website code could be a lot cleaner if I set up a proper templater. I've known this for quite a while, perhaps since near the beginning. The only problem's been that I haven't had any clue how to build one. Today, I slowly worked over the problem, and with what I've learned over the past few years, something's finally clicked into place. I came up with the beginnings of a system, and as I refined the idea, it pretty much turned into a variant of \strtr() wrapped in an object. In fact, I think I can use \strtr() directly for my purposes. If not, very little extra effort will likely be needed to create whatever wrapper I need. I could certainly build a more featureful and problem-specific wrapper around this even if not strictly necessary, but I'm not sure I could justify the overhead using it would generate. The translation of old pages will be a beast.

A new laptop

The Linux laptops at the recycling centre were twice as expensive as last time; and there were two instead of one. When I asked what they recommended, I was told the only differences between the two was that one had a slightly better processor and came with Ubuntu, while the other had a slightly worse processor and came with Linux Mint. They said the difference in processors was so slight that I should choose based on operating system. I said I choose Debian, and that I'd install that myself when I got home, so they said to get the one with the better processor, then they checked for disk drives, and found the Linux Mint one didn't have one anyway. I guess they thought I'd install via CD instead of USB, but still, I'd prefer to have a CD drive over not having one, and the two machines were identically priced. I wouldn't even save money by not having a CD drive.

I got it home and found the Wi-Fi card predictably wouldn't play nicely with Debian. I'd have to swap it out. Unfortunately, it needs the smaller-sized Wi-Fi card, which was currently in bailey. I won't be able to have both laptops usable at once. It was vital that I try the Wi-Fi card in tracy today though, to make sure there wasn't some noxious BIOS DRM that'd prevent the card from being installed later, not to mention that it'd be nice to have Debian already installed when I end up needing this machine. When I opened up bailey to get the card, I found there's a second Wi-Fi card slot, and it takes a card of the bigger size. However, that slot doesn't seem to be operational. I installed my other Wi-Fi card there, but the system doesn't seem to recognise that a Wi-Fi card's installed. Too bad. tracy accepts the small Wi-Fi card though, so I can switch over as long as I'm willing to knock bailey offline to do so. I need to figure out how to get more of these Debian-compatible laptop Wi-Fi cards.

The Wi-Fi issue was only the first of several problems though. The live system I tested tracy's Wi-Fi capabilities with worked fine. However, once installed, the machine couldn't find the operating system. Joy. I did some searching on my borked mobile to see if Debian can even run on this machine. Surely I wasn't the only one having troubles, but surely, if Ubuntu could allow itself to be found, so could Debian. I found nothing helpful (or at least helpful *yet*), but I found some information on problems experienced with these machines on Debian 8. Mostly, Wi-Fi is said not to work without nonfree drivers and the machine's built-in graphics card is said to cause a system crash upon booting unless a bunch of hoops are jumped through. Lovely. I couldn't even get that far though. I tried messing with the BIOS to disable a newer boot system option. I forget what it's called, but I think it works in place of the master boot record or something. I'm pretty sure I managed to disable it and when I tried installing the system again, GRUB got installed to the master boot record instead of whatever it was installed to before. Rebooting, the system started up. Sort of. It crashed on Debian 9, as the article I'd read said it does on Debian 8. I'd already bypassed the Wi-Fi issue by replacing the Wi-Fi card with a better one, so now it was time to fix this issue too.

The instructions say I've got to install the system without a desktop, tinker with some configuration files, then install the desktop. If a desktop is installed before the settings are fixed, the system will crash. The article said it has something to do with the machine's poorly documented, offbeat GPU. I question why this crash doesn't happen on the live system, but at least a fix is available.

A more-pressing question though is how do I install the system without a desktop? I use the live installer. Why do I do that? Because while my Wi-Fi card operates without nonfree firmware, it's broken or something. It disconnects from the network frequently. The network installer, which lets you pick and choose what components to install, isn't designed to handle network interruptions. At all. If the network connection goes down while the installer is downloading packages, the whole installation will lock up. From the system messages, it looks like the installer continues to try to download each package, taking quite a while to give up on each one. Individually. If I wait the *DAYS*-long process of it failing to find the packages, it might present me with an error message and let me reconfigure the network. Maybe. But of course, the Wi-Fi card will fail again, and even assuming the installer keeps what it's already downloaded between attempts (as opposed to starting over every time, which it might also do), it's only going to make a limited amount of progress in each iteration. Assuming packages successfully downloaded are kept between iterations, so progress can actually be made, it'd take well over a month to install the system. It's not feasible.

I've been given a lead as to what to do: use disk one of three of the full, offline installer. I'm told the other two disks won't be needed, which is good, as I'm not sure how to do a multi-disk install using a USB drive. By the time this huge disk finishes downloading though, I hope to be asleep. I have a dental appointment in the morning. If my network connection drops while I'm asleep though, I won't have the disk when I need it.

On the way home from the recycling centre, I stopped at the Cornbread Cafe. The macaroni order I got was disappointingly small, but the burger was unexpectedly large. The burger itself could've been it's own full meal. That was the best I've eaten in a while, and the first time I can remember being full in years. I should make a point of stopping there at least once during each break between terms.

I've eaten there a couple times in the past with my mother, but under her judgemental watch, I don't tent to eat much. Being alone, I was able to get whatever I wanted and enjoy myself.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

The laptop didn't work out

Day 01048: Thursday, 2018 January 18

The dental work continues

From the sounds of it, my biggest cavity, one in the back, wasn't on record. Apparently, only my front one was scheduled to be filled. I'd been looking forward to having both filled today and being done with the dental work for a while. No such luck, but more on that in a bit. Anyway, I pointed out right away that there were two cavities, not one, and they got a radiograph of the back cavity. It seems it's progressed too far though. The tooth can either have a root canal or be extracted, and my insurance won't cover a root canal. Lovely. So I need to have another tooth extracted. This time, the tooth is in the upper back, so there's the risk that ripping it out will tear a hole into my sinuses, according to the consent form they had me sign.

The dentist offered to change plans and perform the extraction during this appointment, but I really wasn't up for another extraction today. Extractions are bad enough when you know they're going to happen, but I'm not emotionally strong enough to deal with them when they're just dropped on me like this. I think I came up with a good enough excuse to put it off, and in fact, putting it off is the smarter option, but underneath it all, it was still an excuse. Anyway, if they extracted the tooth, they said they'd only maybe be able to perform the drill and fill too. It depends on how my body was doing afterwards. The hole in my front tooth is interfering with my eating, while the back one's only a nuisance. More importantly, the back tooth cannot be saved, while the front one probably can. The front one needs to be taken care of before it gets worse.

Some work was done on the front tooth, but it sounds like there's some healing the tooth may or may not do, and depending on that, the tooth may need to either be extracted as well or have a root canal. Being a front tooth, the insurance will cover a root canal, as they have different policies for front teeth. In other words, they're willing to have me go through the horror of an extraction, they just don't want to harm my appearance. It's lovely (pun intended) where their priorities lie. In any case, the filling on the front tooth is temporary and will need to be replaced with a permanent one if the healing goes well. I'm not overly happy with how it came out; it has sharp edges on one side. But as it's not meant to be the permanent filling, I imagine more care will be put in on the new one. Additionally, the dentist patched up the back tooth that will be extracted later, wanting to keep stuff out of the hole. I'm much happier with how that filling came out; it's too bad it'll be removed with the tooth. This also will allow that extraction to be postponed a bit longer. Speaking of which ...

It seems I have more cavities than I realised. There are a couple small ones that'll need to be patched on the twenty-ninth. I imagine the appointment after that will deal with the front tooth again, then the one after that will likely be for the extraction. With the hole in my front tooth currently patched, even if just temporarily, eating will be so much more pleasant than it's been for a while.

As I was mulling over what to do last night and trying to get to sleep, I realised I didn't need to reinstall the system from scratch. What I needed was to edit the configuration files on the hard drive from the live USB system. Or even better, swap the hard drive into the working machine and edit the configuration files from there. As it turned out, swapping the hard drive was the only way; the live system option wouldn't work as I needed to run update-grub after editing them. Still though, it didn't work. The system still crashes when booting. I decided to try to reinstall Ubuntu, the system that came on the machine. If successful, I'd try to get the recycling centre to do an exchange. There might be a reason this machine had Ubuntu when the rest of the Linux systems they sell have Mint. Maybe Ubuntu has certain tweaks that make it work, while the machine Mint is on will play nicer. If the installation failed though, I'm out a bunch of money. I can't return a computer I messed up. I'd have to find a way to make Debian work on it, if even possible. Even if I got it working with Ubuntu though, there's a chance the recycling centre won't take it back.

I set the download to start before running errands for the day, but it wasn't complete by the time I needed to head to work. I figured it'd be done by the time I got off, then I could pull a late-nighter to get the system installed and head out early to return the laptop. It wasn't going to be fun. To make matters worse, I seem to have forgotten to plug my laptop in before heading out. I came home to find it dead. Thankfully, the ISO download had completed by the time the computer ran out of power. Just as thankfully, Canonical provides checksums for their disk images, so I was able to know for sure the download had completed. Otherwise, completed or not, I'd have to assume the file to be partial and throw it out, starting over. Firefox, after all, had no record that the download had even occurred, let alone whether it had completed successfully or not. I think most Linux distributors provide checksums, either to detect tampering, detect broken files, or both. Like the Debian installer, the Ubuntu installer seemed to run just fine on the machine. But would the installed system work correctly, or would it crash like Debian does? I also forgot to put the old Wi-Fi card back into the machine before installing. Would that prevent the proprietary firmware needed to use the thing from getting installed? I'd have to wait and find out. Either way would be a gamble. I could risk continuing to run the installer all for nothing, or I could risk aborting unnecessarily and wasting time that'd already passed.

The Ubuntu install was much, much faster than the Debian installs; the reason for this being that the Ubuntu drive needed to be unencrypted for the next user, and I always encrypt my Debian drives. That meant the drive didn't need to be overwritten to avoid metadata leaks; all the data, meta and otherwise, is just in cleartext. It's so not secure, but it's the state the recycling centre sells them in. They're pushing hardware reuse after all, not encryption. They want the machines to be as easy to get started on as possible.

The good news was that Ubuntu didn't crash, and booted normally. The bad news was that the Wi-Fi didn't work. The other good news was that reinstalling the system fixed the Wi-FI issue. Being a much quicker install (at the cost of being a much less *secure* install), it wasn't even much hassle. I simply worked on journaling in the mean time. Tomorrow won't be fun. I've taken too many trips to Eugene lately, and my knees are sore.

Wi-Fi hardware

I'm tired of not having the Wi-Fi cards I need. The Debian wiki claims that For Mini PCIe all cards with an Atheros chipset are supported.. That seems easy enough, so I bought an Atheros Wi-Fi card online. When it arrives, I'll see if it actually functions. If so, I might grab a couple more.

Website maintenance

Right as I was headed out again, this time to schedule an appointment with a regular medical doctor, my mother wrote to me. So I waited for a response to my response to her, and worked on cleaning the website while I waited. *sigh* Today was not a good day for this, there's too much to get done. It turned out she was in the area and was going to drop by for a visit, but it'd been over half an hour with no response from her. I had to leave before she happened to drop by, and I didn't know she was coming.

I've decided to stop holding back in my coursework. I operate in XHTML, which offers quite a number of features. However, the university website strips out some of those features. I've been trying to tailor my work to work best with the school's system, so I've been refraining from using things such as internal document links, as the university strips id attributes, instead marking everything up with their own, random-looking ids. I'm done caring. The archived copy is now the important thing. Anything allowable in XHTML goes. If it doesn't work with the university's system, too bad.

I was planning to finish the id update today. Really I was. However, there was too much that took away my time. It didn't work out. For example, some of these pages are were a royal mess. Cleaning them up not only drains my time, but my energy. I'm down to two pages though. Just two more pages, and the ids will play nicely with the CSS.

Along the way, I ran into some assignments that involved goal-setting. Most of the goals I set probably still apply, though I'm not quite organised enough to work on them at the moment. The hilarious part to me though is that the school is censoring me, making it highly difficult for me to check this information. The information's still in my reach, but it's prohibitively difficult for me to frequently peruse. They probably wanted me to set the goals to actively keep them in sight, but in an ironic twist, they've made it prohibitively difficult to actually keep the goals in sight and work toward them. Isn't censorship great? If I wanted, I could make a copy of the information and format it into its usable version, keeping that copy in a private location, but what would be the point from my perspective? If the school wants this hidden from the rest of the world, it can remain mostly-hidden from me as well. If I remember, I'll take a look again in 2023.

Medical check-up

I've gotten a medical check-up scheduled now. They'll see me next month on the twelfth, at 11:20. I don't expect it to be eventful.

Learning to drive

A while back, one of my shift leaders offered to teach me to drive. I decided today to take them up on the offer, and ask if it was still open. They're probably my favourite shift leader, they'd already offered, and they're in no way scary, but I was still a bit nervous to ask. I nearly allowed myself to put it off for now, waiting until next month or so to ask about helping me at around April, but decided it was best to ask as early as possible. Sure enough, they're still willing, and as expected, they're busy this month on such short notice. We can't begin now anyway. They say April will be fine, though now that I'm home to check a calendar, it looks like my between-terms period starts a few days before that and is only thirteen days long. And that's if I get my exams taken as soon as possible; otherwise, the gap'll be even shorter. I might have to run the lessons into the terms, shortening the time I have to work on coursework during the week. Joy.

Man in the house

As the head manager headed out, we had a brief little exchange. I won't provide a commentary, but I found it amusing.

"Watch after these girls, you're the only man in the house."

"I'm not a man."

"Close enough."

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

No more energy

Day 01049: Friday, 2018 January 19

I am being worn ragged.

Last night, I looked at my receipt before going to bed, and found the recycling centre has a two-day return policy. I could make the exchange, but I'd need to do it right away. I didn't think to get the Debian ISO download started until I had already headed out this morning. I had to overwrite the image I had on my USB drive to install Ubuntu, so I needed a new ISO image. This cost me several hours. I should've gotten the download started last night. This morning, it was raining, but there was no time to find a clearer day to do this. I don't mind getting a little wet, but I had a cardboard box to carry, so ... yeah. I made it to the recycling centre, where they now have *three* Linux laptops set up. A Web search indicated that two of the laptops, including one of the two that was there two days ago, wasn't likely to play nice with Debian. No matter which of the two I'd bought, I was likely to have problems. The Web seems to indicate one of the new ones will work fine, so I took that one. Next time, I need to do some Web searching before buying so I can have a better chance of avoiding this garbage. There's still a chance of failure, especially because these machines may not include their original parts, but it should weed out a lot of potential problems ahead of time.

I tried the net installer first, as the download was smaller and quicker, but as expected, the Wi-Fi card doesn't work. In needs non-free firmware that I won't provide it. I'll needed to swap my previous Wi-Fi card in, which as stated yesterday, is damaged or something. It frequently disconnects. The Debian installer isn't programmed to handle a Wi-Fi disconnect properly, so the net installer isn't an option. Using that Wi-Fi card, I must install using the live ISO (or something else that contains all the needed packages and doesn't need to retrieve them from online). The larger download predictably didn't complete before I had to go in for my shift at work. This is why I should've started the download before going to bed last night.

When I got home and finally got to test, I was actually pretty hopeful. My hopes were quickly shattered though. I figured I'd perform a quick, unencrypted install to test. If it worked, I'd go to bed. I could reinstall and encrypt tomorrow. Otherwise, I'd begin a Linux Mint download to restore the operating system that came on the machine, and head in to the recycling centre again tomorrow, not having had enough sleep, just like this morning. The actual problem with this new machine caught me off-guard. The BIOS has DRM for preventing you from using your own Wi-Fi hardware! I've seen that once before, and I've been considering it as a possibility in both new laptops I worked with recently, but not on any serious level. I didn't think I'd actually run into that problem again! I don't know what to do. I can't keep biking to the recycling centre. It's not feasible. One thing's for certain: I need to bike to the recycling centre one last time tomorrow and get a refund. Not an exchange, a refund. If I got an exchange, I'd be risking needing to bike there again no later than two days in the future. There'd be no time to rest. I need to put this aside for now. The question is, do I go without a backup laptop for now, or do I order a new laptop that comes with Debian pre-installed? Such a laptop would have zero compatibility issues; I'd be done with this garbage. It'd set me back quite a bit financially though. Is it worth it?

Cornbread Cafe

I stopped at the café again to make a horribly tiring trip a little less bad. I found they weren't serving the good food though; they have a separate breakfast menu. I commented that I wasn't aware of the separate breakfast menu to the waiter, and they seemed rather happy about it, saying they wished they could serve breakfast all day, but the kitchen's not big enough. My thoughts were the opposite though. I wished they'd serve regular food all day, including during breakfast hours. Breakfast foods just aren't very filling or very appetising. I ended up getting some fake scrambled eggs, a pancake, and some potatoes; they were good, but not filling.

Also of note, it seems the café's opening another location, this time in Springfield, several blocks from my home. That'll be great! I can't afford to eat there daily, but I might stop in for a weekly treat to take my mind off coursework. They say they're planning to open in the spring.

PMS

I think I'm PMSing again. First, I nearly cried at the café. (Not about the lack of non-breakfast foods, but about some of the messages plastered on the walls.) I was nearly crying at work yesterday too, if I recall. Then later, as I was going through past goals in my website clean-up, my mind started going to dark places.

It's like this stupid PMS is a side effect of my gayness. During that time span in which I wasn't feeling gay at all, I didn't seem to get PMS any more. Now with my gayness back in full swing, I've got to deal with this crap again. It's certainly worth it, but it's a bit annoying.

Website clean-up

While waiting for the download that didn't complete in time to use before work, I finished up the cleaning of old pages, at least as far as the plan was to clean them. I have no doubt there's a lot of crud left in my journal, but I think the three-month span I set out to fix, as well as the non-journal part of the website, should be mostly crud-free now. But this isn't the end of things. The next step is to build the new template, test its use with \strtr(), and translate all existing pages to use this setup. That's right: all of them. The translation process will take quite a while, and new journal entries will be written only using the new format, as to avoid wasted effort. What this means is that until everything has been translated and the new system is able to go live, new journal entries will not show up during regular website updates. In fact, only two things will likely change on the website during this time: the canary file will be updated and the homepage may or may not show new events.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Physically ill

Day 01050: Saturday, 2018 January 20

This crap is making me physically ill

After waking up, I sort of freaked out a bit because I couldn't move my right arm. After a few seconds though, I remembered. Oh. Right. Sleep paralysis. I forgot that was a thing. I haven't dealt with that in a while.

My nose is all stuffy, and I'm coughing up a storm. I haven't felt this ill in a while. I think it's all the travel. I knew it was taking a lot out of me, but I didn't realise just how much; my immune system is suffering. I nearly didn't head out this morning.

I sort of wavered a bit last night, mulling over the thought of buying brand new hardware to avoid continuing this ordeal. I knew I couldn't actually do that though. I'm way too poor for that. This would need to continue until I find a working computer. I did need to go about it more slowly though, and more stratigraphy. Or so I thought.

First of all, I should never try to buy a computer unless I *already* have the Debian system image. For the first recent computer, I had the image, but I wiped it and still bought (or rather, exchanged for) the second computer anyway. That cost me time. I should probably have both the net installer (in case Wi-Fi works) and live installer (in case it doesn't) on hand. I might want to keep a directory on my external hard drive for simply storing these images between uses so I don't delete my only copies and need to redownload. Second, I shouldn't buy an Hewlett-Packard computer. Ever. The risk of a DRMed BIOS is just too great. It's bad enough when the hardware's functionality is deliberately kept secret so free software can't be built to make the most use of it, but when DRM additionally impedes the replacement of unusable components and makes the whole laptop a brick, we've got a major problem. Third, I need to first install the system unencrypted. I shouldn't go for a usable system right away, but a quick, testing system. If it works out, I'll reinstall and encrypt. Fourth, I should only buy a laptop there when I have at least two days off in a row. On the first day, I buy the machine and test it. On the second day, I return it. No exchanges; only returns. An exchange means that if the next laptop is garbage, I'm stuck going in again.

I decided all this before I left the apartment, then I took the journey at a more-leisurely pace than before. I even shut off my alarm clock last night, then didn't leave the apartment right away when I woke up. After all, I didn't need to rush there and back to have time to test the new machine, because I wasn't getting one. The trip was much less taxing this time, and I actually convinced myself than maybe I *could* keep doing this, as long as I keep my ISOs on hand and don't rush the trip. I got there though, and the recycling centre didn't have anything new for me to try, so I left empty-handed. It's probably a good thing, too. Before leaving, I asked about old G Wi-Fi cards. They don't sell them. I didn't think to ask until I got home, but they probably scrap them like they do the old 32-bit machines! This is why none of the laptops they sell me have working Wi-Fi. They're getting rid of the Wi-Fi cards that work! The simple fact is that the recycling centre's changed since I first started going there. They've probably grown in popularity to the point that they get more donations than they can sell. So they scrap the old stuff, as the new stuff sells better. The new stuff is too locked down and/or too under-documented to be Debian-compatible though. It doesn't matter how many times I return, almost everything I get there isn't going to function now. They care about recycling, but they don't care about freedom. They're scrapping precarious treasures and selling the shiny junk. Only by getting incredibly lucky will I stumble upon a working laptop there. The prices on their lowest-end laptops have gone up since I bought bailey there; they've doubled. Again, it's a sign they're not selling the old stuff any more.

If I get a brand new laptop, it should last longer. Many people throw out their computers after a year or two, when something shinier comes along. Instead, I run my machines until they burn out. If I get a new one, it should last me several years instead of a handful of months, like these last machines have. Speaking of which, these last few laptops I've gotten there haven't lasted long. I sort of wonder if either they're not getting repaired as well as before, either due to lack of caring or as a way to try to drive business up. (You donate the broken computer back to them too, so they get your money for the next machine and they get your last machine to repair and sell again.) I'm not quite ready to break down and buy a new machine, committing to that plan, but I've got a bad feeling about bailey. I think it's going to give up the ghost soon. I can't afford to be without a working machine, and if it dies on me, I can't expect the recycling centre to have a replacement right away, if ever again. I really do need to collect my thoughts, decide on a plan, commit to it, and act.

*sigh* Maybe I'll try one more time. The recycling centre had one laptop that looked like it might work, but the representative said I'd already tried another of that model and it hadn't worked. That didn't seem right, but I didn't think to check my receipt, which I had on me at the time, but had to give them before leaving. I don't know what they're talking about though. It was a Dell Latitude E5500, I think. It was something like that. Remembering I linked to an article on the crashing problem, I basically had a record of what that first machine was; it wasn't a Dell machine of any sort. In a surprise twist, it was a Hewlett-Packard! So I've had two failed machines now, both Hewlett-Packards. Both failures were intentionally caused by the manufacturer: in one case, they kept the details on how to make the hardware function a secret and in the other, they outright installed DRM as a part of the BIOS to deliberately *prevent* the hardware from working. I'm seeing a pattern. Again, I shouldn't buy Hewlett-Packard hardware. Ever. A Dell Latitude {something} though? bailey's a Dell Latitude E6400. I'm typing this journal entry on a Dell Latitude {something}, and Debian's running just fine on it. It's not an exact model match, but Dell hasn't shown me a deliberate desire to cause problems. I really, really don't want to return there tomorrow. And in all likelihood, I don't think I will. I think I'll wait until my new Wi-Fi card arrives in the mail. I'm tired of knocking bailey offline, shutting it down to borrow the Wi-Fi card. Waiting will give me a chance to rest, too. The Dell machine they have in now could very well be gone by the time I get back, but that's fine. I have a better idea of what to avoid now: Hewlett-Packard machines. I can look into whatever else they've got. Then again, I was really feeling the effects of all this travel on my knees at work. Even if I can endure during the trips themselves, I'm not sure I can or should endure the aftermath on a maybe.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Toothaches

Day 01051: Sunday, 2018 January 21

Dental work

It seems each time I get one spot patched up in my mouth, another spot starts hurting. It's like my brain is shutting off the pain signals because there are too many, only presenting me with the worst signals. Then, when those problem areas are resolved, the next ones are revealed. For the past few days, I've been dealing with toothaches on and off. Last night, they kept me from getting to sleep for what felt like hours.

Dream journal

I don't remember most of this dream, but I do recall the ending. I tried to talk to my mobile, which was not only working, but able to accept voice commands as if it didn't have such under-documented hardware that Replicant wasn't able to implement that. I told it to call someone, I forget who, but the thing was in my backpack, so my voice was muffled to it. It misunderstood, thought I'd asked to take over the world, and offered me two people to call to help me with that. The thing was kind of loud, and I was on the clock at some department store, so I shouldn't've been using a telephone at all. I tried to rush to the restroom so I could covertly take the thing out and shut it off, but it seemed to understand I was ignoring it, so it increased the volume.

The two public restrooms were right next to each other, but their signs were confusing to me, slowing me down. One had a silhouette of a man, a woman, a boy, and a girl, all in pink. The other had the same set of people, but this time, they were purple. I thought to myself that if the signs had been identical, they'd clearly be gender-inclusive restrooms, but with the difference in colours, maybe the colour had some significance. I didn't have time for this, and after a few seconds of trying to figure it out, I gave up and used the purple restroom. Across the floor just inside the entrance was a large, deep, trapezoidal basin full of water, like a strange sink with no drain. I was able to step around it, but I remember specifically thinking the placement was terrible because wheelchairs couldn't get around it. And what even was the basin for?

I tried to close the door so I could fiddle with my mobile in piece, but someone was trying to shove their way through the door. I kept telling them it was occupied and shoving back, but they wouldn't listen. Soon, a friend came from the outside and helped me get rid of them, but then *they* were trying to shove their way in! I kept telling them I needed to use the restroom, but they wouldn't listen and kept trying to give me jewellery. I kept getting the door fully closed for a fraction of a second, but when I went to lock it to be done with this, I found there was no doorknob and the only lock was key-operated on the inside of the restroom. I puzzled over how to lock the door for a bit, then it hit me that I somehow had the restroom key. I pulled out my lanyard (the one I use in the real world), and locked the door next time I got it closed. Except ... the friend was able to shove the door open anyway.

On some level, I must've known this was a dream, because I thought that the dream world was cheating. If it was going to cheat, I would cheat a little too. I telekinetically shoved my friend back far enough have a few seconds to lock the door. However, though supposedly locked, the door still wasn't holding closed. After a bit more struggle, the friend won, got the door fully open, and presented me with a few jewellery items.

I pleaded with them to let me have some privacy and let me use the restroom, but they kept excitedly trying to hand me the jewellery. I finally ended up shouting at them, telling them I desperately needed to use the restroom, and they could give me jewellery when I was done. Finally, they got the message and left me alone.

I've got to wonder why my dream self was trying to make a telephone call. I haven't placed a telephone call in over a year; I get out of placing telephone calls for months on end.

Website clean-up

I've refactored the closure that builds the pages of this website into two separate closures. One handles the automated data generation for pages based on their file path, while the other handles the rest of the load the original closure handled. This information from the file path is info that could be (and most of it used to be) stored in the page files, but generating it automatically is less error prone, so a rewrite a while back let me do that. Such information includes the navigation menus for all pages, as well as the subtitles and copyright years for journal pages. Factoring that functionality out puts me in a better position to build the template system, which will replace the second closure altogether.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

It works!

Day 01052: Monday, 2018 January 22

Dream journal

I dreamed my parents were playing a board game with my eldest two siblings, and they were making a mess. I started cleaning up after them, including putting away a second board game they'd left out. My father stopped me, as apparently, the second board game was still in use. They'd started that game first, but put it on hold to play the one they were playing now.

Website clean-up

The transition to a templated system has been a success! I wasn't able to remove the entire second closure today as planned yesterday, but everything is in working order and is much cleaner than before. However, the original plan to go through each page file and clean it ended up not happening. I thought the entire transition would require hand-editing the files, at which point I'd clean them of every mess I noticed them containing. However, I was able to transition the pages to the new format in an almost-automated fashion, in batches of a little over ninety pages at a time. As such, I didn't actually go through the files, so I didn't end up cleaning them. That'll need to be done next time I do major editing in them.

With this main code cleaned up like this, I think my virtual setup is ready for the coming term. Some mess still persists in my virtual workspace, but nothing in the areas I'll be needing for school. I've got a date-related feature I'd like to add that allows the insertion of a journal page's date within the body of the entry, but that can wait until another day. With the new setup, such a feature will be much less daunting to implement than it was when I first noticed a need for it.

I tried to set up automatic validation of page code output, but the WHATWG had to go and mess up the <!DOCTYPE> declaration for HTML5. I knew removing all useful information from the <!DOCTYPE> declaration was a *terrible* idea, even when I first read about it. But now, because of that lack of information, the PHP DOM module can't figure out what kind of document it is and complains that the <html/> element can't be used because it's undefined. On the topic of XHTML and validation, it seems the W3C has released the next version of XHTML: XHTML 5.2, so the footer on my pages has been updated to reflect this. I tried to find an official schema to validate against, as PHPs DOM module can validate markup that way too if I can find the scheme file, but I couldn't find one anywhere. What I did find was this:

I'm aware that WHATWG and W3C have since long moved away from SGML (and XML in most web-related specification work), treating it as a legacy technique and with a somewhat presumptuous attitude in the specification text and elsewhere. But as the analysis of HTML5's grammar shows, they've essentially abandoned use of any formal methods alltogether (and it shows in at least two flaws discussed in the analysis).

Lovely. From the sounds of it, the WHATWG (and according to this author, the W3C) has decided specifications don't need to be formalised with any sort of machine-readable grammar specification. (In reality, the W3C only joined in on the WHATWG's plan because the W3C would've lost all influence on XHTML/HTML otherwise. The W3C's participation is not a sign that they agree with the WHATWG, and the WHATWG's plans seem to be almost exactly the opposite of the direction the W3C wanted to take the Web.) That means there's no way to validate XHTML5 documents without an XHTML5-specific validation tool. No generic tool will do a complete and accurate job. This is a huge part of why standards matter, and the WHATWG have really trashed an important Web standard.

Apartment cleaning

With my virtual space cleaned, it's now time to get back to cleaning my physical space. My main work for the day was moving furniture and planning the moving of more. I removed the coffee table from my bedroom. It was I think the first piece of furniture I brought in, but it's in terrible shape. Someone had been throwing it out and I scooped it up. I also moved a different table in to use in its place. It's got more space on it and it looks a lot nicer. I'll probably get rid of the first table once I've moved things around a bit more.

Wi-Fi card

The new (er, used) Wi-Fi card arrived in the mail today. I didn't get a chance to try it before work, but it was the first thing I did when I got back home. The suspense was killing me. The most-likely scenario in my mind was that the card wouldn't work on my running system, but that it'd be completely usable from the live system. My reasoning was that the installer probably wouldn't have installed the firmware for it, as it wasn't needed at the time of installation. If this was indeed what came to pass, I should be able to switch back to my faulty Wi-Fi card to have Internet service at all, then use it both to look up how to install the firmware from the main Debian repo and to perform the actual installation itself. A nagging fear in my mind said the card wouldn't work at all, on the installed system or on the live system, but that fear was mostly held back by thoughts that the Debian wiki wouldn't lie to me. When I installed the card and booted the system, I was pretty sure I saw a message flash by about Atheros firmware that failed to load. I figured this was exactly what I'd imagined happening coming to pass, that the firmware was missing on my specific machine, but that I'd find it in the installer/live system where I needed in most. Instead, once I was logged in, I found the Wi-Fi working just fine. It's not even a struggle to remain connected any more! Before I headed into work, I was beating my head against the wall trying to get connected just long enough to even send an email ... it was painful. Now, I seem to stay connected just fine, and I didn't even have to instruct the machine to connect in the first place; it just chose a network from the list of one's I've instructed it to connect to automatically.

I need more of these cards. There's no time tonight, but I need to go back and buy a few more from that seller; I think I recall they had several.

To Eugene again ...

I was sort of considering heading to Eugene tomorrow to try my hand at getting a working laptop again, even before the Wi-Fi card arrived. I've rested a bit; I'm running out of time before school starts; and I have the day off tomorrow, so I can make the trip at my own pace. The fact that the Wi-Fi card arrived though means I'll definitely be going. I needed rest, but the Wi-Fi card was my actual excuse to put the trip off.

I should go about this more strategically than before; I should bring supplies and test the laptop before leaving the city to return home. At a minimum, I should bring a screwdriver, the large Wi-Fi card, one of the small Wi-Fi cards, and the USB drive with the live system on it. I need to use the live system to test the Wi-Fi, which almost certainly wont work, then swap in one of the Wi-Fi cards I brought and test again. I won't do a full system install until I get home, so there could still be problems like with that first of the two recent laptops, but I should be able to rule out the most likely problems right then and there. Lastly, I should remember not to buy a Hewlett-Packard machine, under any circumstances.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

No more recycling centre laptops

Day 01053: Tuesday, 2018 January 23

Apartment cleaning

Today's main cleaning project was to move everything I've gathered and am storing form my mother into the living room, where she's supposed to be storing her stuff. She still hasn't brought a single item over, but I've gathered several items I think she'd want. Cat litter buckets, children's books, crayons ... If it turns out she's not interested, we can just give any of these away; they didn't cost me a dime. I was just in the right place and time to get them. I've been storing them in my own space, but she's not even *using* her storage space and these items are here for *her*

I've also cleared *everything* out of my bedroom unless it has a specific place in there it belongs. If all goes well, I'll get it all sorted tomorrow and have what should belong in there put back in specific spots.

Potatoes

A coworker of mine told me potatoes are bad for joint health, especially when you're going to be exercising, such as on my bike trips to Eugene. My breakfast options for the day were either leftover potato gnocchi and peas or leftover fake cheese bread, and the cheese bread didn't seem very appetizing, so I did some research online. I little at all indicating that potatoes have any effect whatsoever on joint health, and what I did see was all rumours, and have not even been scientifically studied. Of these rumours, most of them only applied to people with existing arthritis, anyway.

I did find an interesting passage completely unrelated to joint health though:

These days, the most common potatoes, like Russets, also tend to have the lowest amount of glycoalkaloids (see Stephan’s chart); this is no accident, instead being the product of generations of careful agricultural selection by farmers. Throughout history, then, humans have tended to avoid the bulk of potato glycoalkaloids, either unwittingly, by peeling potato skins, or by selecting the low-glycoalkaloid varieties that didn’t provoke stomachaches, digestive issues, or inflammation and sold well at the market.

We've altered the evolution of potatoes, or at least the common varieties of them that we tend to eat. It's yet another example of how we humans tend to change the species around us to better suit our own purposes. In this case, we've reduced the glycoalkaloid content; glycoalkaloid is used by potato plants to keep away pests that would otherwise feed on them. Pests such as us.

Laptop shopping

Usually when I go into the recycling centre, I'm dealing with clerks that seem a bit geeky. They understand that the hardware doesn't work for all purposes, and they don't seem to have a problem with my returns. However, this time, I dealt with someone who was more of a businessperson than a geek. They don't like that I keep bringing laptops back, and they've informed me that they're putting a cap on my returns now. It was unclear whether the laptop I'd just bought before they informed me of the cap they were placing on me could be returned at all after leaving the store, so I returned it right away. After all, it wasn't like they could refuse the return when they hadn't informed me beforehand that the cap was now in place, and it sounded like I wouldn't be able to return it this time.

Furthermore, it seems that unlike the geeks, they don't like me exchanging the operating system on the machine. They don't seem to understand that changing the operating system isn't at all different from changing the installed applications, and that a computer isn't useful when you can't change the software to match your needs. When I returned it, I explained I was doing so because I couldn't guarantee the machine would even work. They kept trying to claim that the machines work perfectly when they sell them, and that by changing the operating system, I'm the one to blame for the dysfunction; I should buy the machine, not swap the operating system, and not return it. Um. No. The machine doesn't work that way, as it it doesn't do the things I need it to do. Leaving Linux Mint on the machine makes the thing unusable, as I can't trust it with my data. Besides, their hardware is wonky. Some of it is simply under-documented because the manufacturer wants to be stupid and secretive. Technically, that hardware itself isn't wonky, just the conditions that surround it are. That's not *my* fault. Some of their hardware has actual DRM in it though. That hardware *is* wonky. The DRM itself probably isn't in the hardware itself, but the firmware, however, it's highly likely the hardware's designed to reject firmware that isn't signed by the manufacture, in which case the hardware is still, by design, wonky.

In any case, it seems I can't use the recycling centre to procure laptops unless I want to risk buying machines that don't function at all for my purposes; basically giant paperweights. I could still use them for parts, but not really. I could get hard drives and RAM there, except that I already have more of those things than I need. I could get Wi-Fi cards there, but if they're under-documented, I'm going to be blamed for the fact that they don't work, so I won't be able to return them.

With this recycling centre being unreasonable, and with no other known computer-recycling centres in the area, my only choice now is to buy online. I've been wavering back and forth between continually trying the recycling centre and buying a new machine online, but now, it looks like my options are limited. I have no choice now but to buy a new machine.

Errand day

Today turned out to be mostly an errand day. I took my trip to Eugene, I ran my regular Tuesday errands (checking the Bi-Mart lucky numbers and depositing my pay cheque at the credit union), dropped off my ballet of the election, went out to buy groceries, and washed my laundry for the week. Still, I got a fair amount done in the apartment too. During my errands, my bike seat came loose though, making it difficult and painful to ride. If I'd remembered, I'd've found my wrench while i was moving stuff out of my bedroom and tightened the thing up, but now, that's not an option until tomorrow. I moved everything out into piles, so finding any specific item isn't feasible. It'll have to wait until I've sorted everything.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Cleaning and resting

Day 01054: Wednesday, 2018 January 24

Cleaning

I was planning to complete the organisation of the stuff I removed from my bedroom today, but what I wasn't planning for was the exhaustion that hit me. Yesterday was a physical drain.

I got some more furniture moved. Mostly, I moved another table into the bedroom along with a chair. The tables are, for the most part, much more useful in my personal space, where I can use them to hold both items I want safely behind my locked door and items that aren't necessarily great to show off. For example, I have a pile of scrapped laptops I need to finish dismantling when time allows. Do I want that on a table in my entryway? Probably not. I'd move then to the living room table, but ... my living room is still "in use" by my mother. I've also gotten my clothing organised, so it's easier to choose an outfit for the day. I also sorted numerous smaller items, and aside from the paperwork I need to sort and file away, all unsorted stuff from my bedroom has been confined to a single laundry basket. There's no much left to sort, but what's left has no obvious place to belong. I also have stuff remaining in other locations, mostly on the one table remaining in the entryway, which also need to be gone through. My five-day work week starts again tomorrow, which will slow me down, but hopefully I will get at least a little done each day. After that, I have two more days off, and then work and school will begin again together.

I managed to find my wrench, though not in the sort of the stuff from my bedroom. With the nuts on the seat tightened, my bike should be ready for my commute tomorrow.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Further healing

Day 01055: Thursday, 2018 January 25

Driving lessons

I finally got a chance to talk to my driving instructor about the shortness of my time in April. I told them whenever they have time will be fine, and I'll just have to make time if I don't have it. I won't sleep as much as I should, if I have to. I'm running short on time and I need to get this done.

May I pay in change?

I had a customer come through the drive-through today and pay for their order entirely with pennies. Of course, I had to count them all. I don't mind counting pennies. Honestly, I don't. I found it mildly amusing, at the time. A lot of people get annoyed if you try to pay in pennies, but they're ignoring the fact that they're being *paid* to count them. They're on the clock It's not a difficult task, and if you're not counting someone's pennies, you're performing some other (likely also boring) task.

Now that I think on it though, it was sort of rude for them to bring all those pennies through the drive-through and make me count them. If they'd brought them into the lobby to pay, that'd be one thing, but they held up the whole drive-through line. Whatever though; nothing I could do about it, and not my concern.

Gum healing

Sometimes it's one of my front teeth that hurts, other times it's the gaping hole in my gums on the right side, where three teeth were extracted. I was still feeling the hole in its full size, a couple days ago. I mean, my gums were elongating and trying to cover the hole, but they hadn't grown far enough yet to do more than just form a flap. Today though, I noticed that it feels like along about half the width of the crack, in the long direction, the sides have merged. The hole will be gone soon. Yay!

Just in time for a new hole to be ripped in the upper side of my mouth. Ugh.

Wi-Fi card

On that first night I tried the new Wi-Fi card, I mentioned that it doesn't get disconnected every few seconds, and just remains connected as it should. Well ... It hasn't been acting that way *since* that first night. It doesn't get disconnected every few seconds, but for the past three days, it *has* been disconnecting every few minutes. It stays connected longer that that other Wi-Fi card, that's for sure, but it's still not staying connected like it should. It may be the poor signal quality in my apartment though, especially given the drastic improvement. The other Wi-Fi card had problems, that is undeniable, but the problems this new one's experiencing might not be because of the card itself.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

I do dildos, not drugs.

Day 01056: Friday, 2018 January 26

Gum healing

This morning, when I awoke, I found the hole in my gums shrunk to about half what it was last night when I went to bed. If I'm lucky, the hole will be gone tomorrow. The hole's presence is made worse by the prescription toothpaste I have to use. The toothpaste gets in the hole, but I'm not supposed to rinse after brushing, or the medicated toothpaste won't have its effect. Once in the hole, the hole feels like it's burning for about twenty minutes, making it difficult to go to sleep.

apartment cleaning

Today wasn't the most productive day ever, but I did finish with the entryway table area. The table had been covered in miscellaneous items I'd been setting there for at least a month, with the intent to sort them later. I also finally got the leaf inserted. There was no space for the table in its wide form before; everything's been cramped since I cleared the living room for my mother's use. I've had to store the leaf in the water heater's closet, which got in the way of the use of the shelves in there. With my bedroom better organised though, I've been able to move more stuff into here, freeing up space around the table in the entryway.

They gave me marijuana!?

I had a customer that came through drive-through drop strange plant matter in my tip jar. I highly suspected it was marijuana, so I asked them what it was. They acted incredibly shifty though, and wouldn't give me a straight answer. They just kept telling me it was "medicine". Medicine for what? After asking what it was for a few times, they finally told me it helps with pain, but still wouldn't tell me what it was. A friend and coworker of mine's a user though, so I asked them if it was in fact what I thought it was. Yup. Sure enough, I've been given a dose of weed.

They said it's a hybrid species, mostly stativa, partly indica, but they couldn't identify the exact strain. That's more specific than I was looking for though! I just wanted to know the general nature of what this person had given me. They told me the drug should make me very happy and giggly, but I've already got something that has that effect on me: my dildo. I'm curious as to how similar the drug's effects are to the aftermath of an orgasm, but not curious enough to give it a try.

Now that I've gotten it home and had a chance to examine it a bit, I find it smells incredibly familiar. It took me a bit to place the scent, but I think it smells like mint! I don't know. Anyway, I guess I'll keep it on my shelf for now as an amusing reminder of today, but as I'm not a user, it's not something I can actually make use of. I'm still in disbelief that a random stranger gave me drugs, without any hint that I might even want them; without any indication that I'd even know how to use it. Seriously. I have no idea what to do with this plant. I guess people smoke it, but how does one do that? There's probably more to it than rolling it in paper and lighting it on fire. I could look it up if I really cared, but to do that, I'd first have to find a way to identify it as marijuana to begin with. In my case, I had a hunch and it panned out, but since the customer wouldn't give any real hints as to what it was, they couldn't realistically expect me to get that far.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Winding down and preparing for the coming term

Day 01057: Saturday, 2018 January 27

Dream journal

I dreamed Cyrus had come back to town to live with our mother for a while. Our mother was thoroughly railing on him though because of some of the shirts he'd brought with. They were just a solid orange with white trimming; nothing offensive in any way. Cyrus' room mate and I were flabbergasted by our mother's behaviour.

I also found a pair of praying mantises in what was to become Cyrus' bedroom. I started caught them to take them outside, but smaller insects started getting on my arms and in my armpits, which was unpleasant. I looked where I'd found the mantises, and saw two more. I thought they were the same two, but then realised I was still holding the original two. I'd stumbled upon a total of four mantises. I've never seen so many in one place! I'm not even sure I've ever seen two of the creatures together before.

Gum healing

My gums didn't finish healing over as I'd hoped overnight. In fact, I can't feel any noticeable difference. I got my hopes way too far up.

That said, the pain in my tooth has gone down immensely. Yesterday, I hadn't needed to use my water trick to make the pain bearable. Today, there was so little pain that it's barely worth even mentioning. I'm kind of wondering if the pain I felt before had either radiated from the hole or was felt in the wrong place due to a crossed signal in my nerves or something.

Apartment cleaning

My cleaning task for today was small and simple: return bottles for deposit at two convenience stores, getting them out of my entryway. I decided yesterday I'd do it today, but I very nearly didn't out of laziness. That's another one hundred bottles out of my home though, and they're back down to a manageable level. If I can look into the box and easily see there's less than fifty without counting them, I'm golden.

I guess tomorrow's task should be working on that laundry basket of miscellaneous junk. When I get that sorted, I'll probably quit the cleaning projects for now. Well, aside from file-sorting. The rest of the disorder here is insignificant, and I'm really not up for getting obsessive about organisation for the time being. I've already made huge improvements, especially in my bedroom. As I said, I had to move a lot of junk into my bedroom from my living room to clear space for my mother, but part of the living room had started messy. I never cleaned up a two piles made when I first moved in and had to get everything transported as quickly as I could muster. Both of those ended up in my bedroom when I cleared the living room, but now they're actually sorted and dealt with. This might be the cleanest I've had the place since I got here. I have a few unsorted items on shelves, but that's about all the mess that's left.

Domain hunt

My notes indicate that the //pr. registry uses a manual process of approving domain names and that I've actually tested their form, though I never completed a purchase. Things seem to have changed since then though. there's no longer any trace of an on-site method of registration, and the only way to register a domain is to go through an accredited registrar. I've updated my main notes accordingly, and removed the //pr. ccTLD from my usable ccTLDs list.

For a while now, I've been considering getting a second domain name to use for providing certain services. I actually found the issue with the code>//pr. registry because I was considering using their ccTLD and needed to do a little more research first. I've got a couple different ideas about how I might want to go about finding a name. On one hand, I've got a fun experiment I'd like to try. I'd love to discuss this in depth, but this journal is public and the experiment would be unduly harmed if the nature of the experiment were discovered. Once the experiment ends, if I end up performing it, I'll disclose the full details. On the other hand, I could go for a more stable option and simply take the easy route. Whether I decide to perform the experiment not only determines the SLD I decide on, but also determines what TLD I use. I fear I may already be saying too much ... If you know me well and you know domain names well, my entire experiment can probably be guessed just from this paragraph alone. (In particular, note my inconsistent use of terms.) Anyway, I'll probably look into multiple TLDs and try to decide on the SLDs that pair best with both the TLDs and my intent for the domains.

Visit

With most of the major stuff I need to accomplish before my break ends complete, I paid my mother a visit after work. It seems she's got some heavy stuff she needs moved, but my schedule and her timeline don't match up, so I unfortunately can't help. Her place is a royal mess, even more so than mine ever was, and she just bought a new washing machine. She's not planning to clear a path tonight, so I can't help her move it tomorrow morning. She's going to clear the path tomorrow morning and afternoon, then move the washer in the evening, but I have work in the evening. She doesn't want to wait until I'm free on Tuesday, and I really can't blame her. It's a real pain not having a washing machine.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Making do

Day 01058: Sunday, 2018 January 28

I dreamed a coworker of mine was having problems with the printer at work as I was headed home for the day and asked me to figure out the problem. The first issue was that it was out of printer paper. The next issue was that it was jammed full of miscellaneous paper, including both used printer paper and used notebook paper. I went to the head manager to ask where to find more printer paper, but they were busy dealing with a customer, so I went and looked for it myself. I searched and searched, but couldn't find any.

Apartment cleaning

As previously planned, I finished my sorting today. Aside from my current lack of a backup laptop and the fact that my physical files are still in disarray, I'm about as prepared for the coming term as I can be.

Makeshift music player

With my mobile out of commission, not having an alternate music player has been annoying. I can't afford a new mobile device though, at least not for the time being, and I'm not convinced getting one later will be necessary either. Until a device exists in which the hardware plays nicely with free software ... any mobile I get will be severely gimped. I'm not sure having one is even worth it. I considered getting a dedicated music player, but ever one of them I can find, if they even support Vorbis files at all, has the same fatal flaw: they require use of a FAT filesystem. FAT filesystems, in addition to their annoying case insensitivity, require me to rename all my music files to avoid using certain characters, such as question marks and colons. I name my files based on their album name, album artist name, track number, and track name. For example, Josh Woodward's Sunny Side of the Street album, which has no album artist metadata, has a song called "Are You Having Fun?" as track eleven. I've predictably named the file [Sunny Side of the Street][]{11}{Are You Having Fun?}.ogg. This file won't transfer to a FAT filesystem unless I rename it first. Marc With a C has several tracks on Right Where I Am with colons in their titles: the entire Bootwater Suite. Professor Shyguy's Unplugged: Please Check Connection and Marc With a C's Good Clean Fun: Marc With a C Sings The Monkees! albums themselves have colons in the names. I think that the exclamation point in that last one might also cause FAT filesystems to choke. These are not uncommon characters, and it's not unreasonable to expect to be able to use them! Marc uses asterisks, again, forbidden by FAT, to censor some titles as well. I had the work of an artist in my library until recently too that used a whole tonne of garbage characters from Unicode in their titles, and some (but not all) also cause FAT filesystems to throw a fit. Anyway, my point is that I can't go through and look for all the characters FAT will choke on and replace them with something else. It's not feasible.

I came up with the beginnings of a solution last night. Well, not a solution, but a bandage with which to cover the problem with. The only *real* solution is to abandon FAT filesystems. Anyway, the bandage was an idea for a script that would take the names of tracks in my music library, encode every octet as a hexadecimal pair, and copy the file under the new name to a player. My no-album track directory would be treated as special: the directory name would be copied as-is instead of encoded, as Replicant treats the directory name of tracks without album names as the name of the album. Tracks with no track name would be given special treatment as well: they wouldn't have their file names changed, as again, Replicant treats the file names as the track names in such cases. I imagine other players take a similar approach.

It seems though that the Vorbis PECL module isn't available in the Debian repositories. Sure, I could install it from elsewhere, but for just my own personal use, it seems like overkill. I decided to work with the existing file names instead. I soon realised I didn't need the encoding to be reversible though. I don't need to encode anything. A simple *hash* of the file names is all I need; that'll prevent overlapping file names on the FAT side well enough. That's certainly easier to implement than an encoder; the hashing functions are already built into the language.

I'm going to be using an old Android as a music play for a while. It's less expensive than a dedicated music player, and has about the same problems as well. Android uses an ext4 filesystem or something of that nature for internal storage, but refuses to read ext{anything} filesystems on SD cards. This device cannot be trusted (as the source code is unavailable and unauditable), but I think as long as I don't connect it to the network (keep it in aeroplane mode) and I don't give it any personal information, it should be fine. I'm unsure of the implications of using the device's camera, so I won't be using that either, at least for the time being. This thing'll only be used for music playing and setting a timer for my breaks at work.

I was in a rush to get this thing set up for work, so the first implementation of my bandage was the one I went with. I didn't even apply the special treatment to that one directory. All the file names are scrambled, and it's nearly impossible to find any particular file you're looking for. The music player application makes sense of it all and displays the correct names (when correct names are available in the metadata), but I anticipate it'll be a pain to add new music. I'll probably come up with a more-sophisticated script later. Likely, it'll hash the initial names (to avoid overlapping filenames when characters are stripped), strip the characters that FAT chokes on, then insert the hash between the file extension and the rest of the filename.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Shaving

Day 01059: Monday, 2018 January 29

Dream journal

I dreamed I was cleaning out a huge motor home I'd acquired and was setting it up for my personal use. The inside seemed bigger than the outsides, and there were several unexpected things in there, such as filing cabinets and computer systems.

Dental work

It seems when the dentist was talking about the filling in front being temporary and needing to revisit that tooth, they were referring to a lot longer out than I was expecting. They want to check that tooth out again in half a year; I was thinking of just a couple months.

The work today went smoothly, but it seems I have a couple more visits to go before they finish drilling and filling. I'm unsure why that can't be done all at once, but at least this isn't as traumatic as the extractions, so it's not really a bother. My only concern is that putting off the drilling/filling until the next appointment raises the risk of further erosion. My next appointment is on February sixth. I guess that'll be before this journal entry even goes live.

Makeshift music player

I've decided that for my more-sophisticated music player, I only even want to rename specific files and directories that are problematic. I'd been considering including a hash of all original names and appending it to the file names, but when no characters need to be stripped, this isn't exactly necessary. When I went to implement this, the easiest way I found was to use \str_replace() to replace unsupported characters with an empty string. If I'm using \str_replace() anyway, I might as well replace the characters with some sort of escape-sequence-like string, so that's what I did. In theory, I should've encoded my escape character if I was going to do that, but I didn't. Doing so would either require an extra pass of name-alteration or would potentially cause filenames that needn't be modified to be modified anyway. It just wasn't worth the bother. As I said before, the name-alterations don't even need to be reversible. I just need to reduce the likelihood of name clashes caused when renaming while at the same time keeping the filenames recognisable enough that I can find what I'm looking for.

I also learned something about VFAT, the version of FAT used by Android for the SD card filesystem. When filenames are too long to meet the 8.3 criteria, they're case *sensitive*. Sweet! Windows covers this up by performing extra checks to ensure new files created don't have similarly-named counterparts with differing cases. However, Linux currently does not. That means that as long as moderate- to long-sized filenames are used, Linux allows users to take advantage of the case-sensitivity of this filesystem format. The person asking about it on the linked page considers it to be a bug in the Linux VAT driver, but if it acted any differently, I'd consider it to be an anti-feature in the driver. It's not the driver's job to prevent the user from using perfectly-valid file names to mimic a poorly-thought-out feature in a more-popular operating system. Seriously. Case-insensitivity is stupid.

The experiment

I've been meaning to try an experiment for a while: shaving. Why do girls shave their legs? Just enjoy your natural form! Shaving is stupid, right?

I haven't had time to try it myself really, but with school starting back up soon, I'm running out of time to just relax and wind down from last term. I think I'll mostly take the next couple days off. After my dental appointment, I took a relaxing bath, and during it, I decided to try out shaving. I decided to only shave one leg though, so I could more easily see the difference. And wow, what a difference it makes. My leg looks ... younger, I guess? And certainly more refined; less rugged. It's the same as with my face. It feels nicer too, aside from when I rub the upward against the stubble. I think I like this. I might change my mind in the next while, so I'll leave the other leg alone for now, but I'll likely make shaving them both a regular thing. And probably my arms as well. I wonder though if there's a way to reduce the stubble issue.

Errands

It's true I think I'm going to mostly relax for a couple days, but I do need to get a few things done. Tomorrow is Tuesday. That means I have my weekly trip to Bi-Mart. I should start keeping track of the winning digit each week to see if there's a pattern. I'm obviously not going to win the big prizes, so if there's a pattern to the single-digit prize numbers, I'll be able to predict whether it's even worth making the trip. On busy weeks I'm not going to win, I can stay home ans study. On slow weeks, I can head in whether I'll win or not just for the exercise.

I forgot to pick up my rent cheque last week too, so I need to pick one up while I'm out. I'd also like to talk with a representative at the mobile store that sells the model I'm using as a music player. (They probably quit carrying this model, but it still bears their logo, so maybe they'll help.) The device refuses to allow me to specify just a single song to play. I can specify an album, or I can add single songs and albums to the currently-playing list, but to even *start* the currently-playing list, I have to specify an entire album or artist's collection to use. That's just idiotic. I'm doubting there's a way around it, but it doesn't hurt to ask. After that, I should get my laundry washed for the coming week.

I feel like there are other errands I need to run tomorrow in that trip, but I can't for the life of me recall what they are. I'd love to avoid needing to make a second trip later.

University drudgery

Okay, so I've been dealing with a couple people at the school about the continued ambassador group issue. I haven't been discussing it here in my journal for a couple reasons though. First of all, I recently went back through my journal and found old pages oozing with toxicity. I don't want to be toxifying more new pages than I have to. Second, I don't have much need to detox, or vent to the journal. Discussing these school issues is actually causing me more stress than it resolves. Anyway ...

It seems the school's walled garden within the Microsoft social network allows students in using their own email addresses once they've been sent an invitation, but it doesn't give them as much access as they need. Some groups, such as the ambassador group, only allow students in when they're using the secondary accounts associated with their school-assigned email addresses. I may or may not have written about that already. I don't recall, so I figured I'd write about it again here just to be safe. And why do schools assign their own email addresses to students? This is stupid. Is it just a way to get students to spread the word about the school by spreading the school's domain?

Okay, so having learned of this situation from the first person I was dealing with, I proceeded to tell them about the name change and how, being a gender issue, using my then-current university email address wasn't an option, as the address contained my birth name instead of my real (and also legal) name. I continued, asking how to get my university email address updated to correct the problem. So what do they do? They explain how to update my main email address on file with the university; the one they won't let me use to join the ambassador group with. Um. Really? I guess they thought this was what I was asking about, but you'd have to be a complete and total moron to think that. Why would I suddenly jump ship on the topic at hand, to ask about an unrelated issue that happens to also involve email addresses? Clearly, they weren't following the fact that the university-assigned email address was the one I had to use, despite being the one to tell me I had to use it. If the person in charge of the ambassador program can't even follow their own bouncing ball, it's no wonder I lost touch with the program so quickly. I thought maybe I'd somehow missed the fact that most communications would be via this social network, but it likely wasn't made clear at all. Anyway, once they understood the problem, they redirected me, asking me to ask my academic advisor to help.

My academic advisor is usually pretty good, so I'll give them the benefit of the doubt this time. They didn't seem to listen to the problem as I described it, and came to the wrong conclusion. After reiterating and re-emphasising, they appeared to have a firm grasp on the issue at hand. They pretty much backed up what the first person had told me, that I couldn't use my primary account, and said they'd try to get the university-assigned email address fixed. It took a few days, as they ostensibly had to delegate to other people who manage the email accounts, but they got back to me today saying the email address was fixed. They gave me a new email address and new temporary password, so I assumed it was a new account. I entered it into my KeePassX database as such, though upon logging in, I found it was the same account, updated. That's exactly what they should have done, for a multitude of reasons. When I went to delete the old entry for the account, I found something interesting though: a note about the password length being capped at sixteen characters. When password lengths are capped or passwords appear to be unhashed, I make a note of it. Over a year ago, when I first was given the account, Microsoft was capping password lengths there to sixteen characters. Ouch. My new password is sixty-four characters long though, the maximum the Debian 9 version of KeePassX will do. (Debian 8's version had no limit, if I recall.) That was a major security issue, in my opinion, but at least Microsoft fixed it at some point.

The domain name search has ended

I decided not to experiment with the domain name. I want a fairly stable name to use with shared and potentially-shared services that might last, such as IRC and public projects. I tried out some partly-random names before work, mostly combining words that sounded good with the word "project" or "collective". Nothing was really panning out though. At work, I decided on a cool domain name that wasn't at all random, but was likely taken. Thankfully, when I got home, I found the exact match I wanted was available! The //com. variant is registered, but doesn't seem to be in use. It doesn't even have a parking website attached to it, though it might be used for non-Web services. In any case, it seems unlikely a domain squatter has it. I was leaning toward an //org. domain though, and given the SLD I came up with, I think //net. would be more appropriate. The name under both TLDs is available. I tried a shorter variant as well; not that I wanted it, but I thought I'd see if the name was in use and I should choose another instead. It seems the //net. version of the short domain has a squatter, while the //com. and //org. versions are registered, but with no website. In any case, I don't think the name's seeing any major use, so I shouldn't run into problems using the name myself.

I considered purchasing the domain at the start of the coming term. That'd give me a couple days to mull it over, and maybe begin setting up a website for it. I need a VPS, which will host the website, but also other services such as IRC and, if I ever get around to it, Minetest. After thinking on it most of the day at work, I realised I don't want the date of registration aligned with the start of the term though. If I register it then, that date will forever be etched into the domain's whois record. Any random date would be better than one based on the school. Instead, I think I'll wait a little over a month, and register on the renewal date for my personal domain. It's an anniversary, and anniversaries are stupid to base things off of, but it'll allow me to only have one renewal date to remember to pay by. Maybe it's stupid to wait and potentially lose the domain, but I'm not comfortable committing with less than even a day to decide for sure.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.

Another broken key

Day 01060: Tuesday, 2018 January 30

Running errands

The Bi-Mart lucky ending digit for this week was 8. Last week, it was 4.

The mobile shop was unable to help. It took forever to get the representative to understand the problem, and when they finally did, they didn't see how it could possibly be a problem. They also said there was no workaround, it's just how the player functionality works. Maybe I should connect it to the network long enough to install F-Droid and find a better player on it.

While I was out, I picked up four cans of vegetable juice. I got charged a deposit! What a pain. It seems that because people are too lazy and inconsiderate to recycle their cans, we've now got to go through the added effort of lugging them back to the store. And you can bet the convenience stores won't be taking them, as they don't sell them, so I've got to lug them even further. Joy. From what I can gather online though, they shouldn't be charging a deposit on these. Cans that require a tool to open (for example, a can opener) are exempt from the bottle bill. *sigh* I guess I shouldn't bring it up to them that they made a mistake though. It's a pain for me, but maybe it'll get more cans recycled and more metal reused. I need to hold onto my receipts though, in case they try to go back on this and not give me my deposit back. Actually, never mind. It seems I've already misplaced it. I might've lost it when I pulled it out to talk with customer service about a different accidental overcharge. Next time though.

My new U-lock has been rusting. The old one was difficult to work with from the start, but this one was functional before the rust. I was just thinking today that at least this lock's key has a sturdier build - none of this hollow key crap - so even though I had to wrestle with the lock, at least I could still make it work. I was considering hitting up the bike shop later to ask what they suggested, thinking they'd likely tell me to use some sort of lube. At my final stop though, I couldn't open the lock, and the key broke off. Again. Joy. The key may not be hollow like the other one, but it's also stupidly not solid metal. A bike lock shouldn't be sold in this half of the state if it can't stand up to a little wet weather. That's all we get around here. All I can think is that it's lucky it broke when it did. If it'd instead broken off one use later or one earlier ... the bike'd be locked up again with no way to get it off. Just like last time.

I'm done with these U-locks for now. I've had nothing but trouble with them. Tomorrow, maybe I'll walk down to the bike shop, explain the issue, and ask what they recommend.

Copyright © 2018 Alex Yst; You may modify and/or redistribute this document under the terms of the GNU GPLv3+. If for some reason you would prefer to modify and/or distribute this document under other free copyleft terms, please ask me via email. My address is in the source comments near the top of this document. This license also applies to embedded content such as images. For more information on that, see licensing.

W3C standards are important. This document conforms to the XHTML 5.2 specification and uses style sheets that conform to the CSS3 specification.